<?xml version="1.0"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Library of Congress Finding Aids</title>
  <id>http://findingaids.loc.gov</id>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/feed.xml"/>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu012015.2</id>
    <title>Peggy Clark Papers</title>
    <updated>2012-09-24T14:21:34</updated>
    <summary>The Peggy Clark Papers span the period 1880-1997 with the bulk of the materials dating from 1936-1970. Contents include light plots, scenic renderings, blueprints, correspondence, published and unpublished writings, programs, photographs, posters, scripts, scrapbooks, clippings, notes, audio cassettes, and memorabilia.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu012015.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2012-07-20T15:01:50</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu012018.2</id>
    <title>Music from the Bob Hope Collection </title>
    <updated>2012-09-24T14:21:34</updated>
    <summary>Music from the Bob Hope Collection consists of manuscript and photocopied full scores, conductor's scores, parts, lead sheets, and lyric sheets for nearly 500 titles used in Hope's films, television programs and personal appearances. Many of the arrangements were written for short play-on and play-offs, interludes, and cues for Hope's television specials and USO tour appearances. The collection also includes fully arranged songs written for solo or duet performances by notable guests on the Bob Hope Show. Most of the arrangements were written by Bob Alberti, Nick Perito and J. Hill. Additional arrangers represented in the collection include Frank Comstock, Manny Harmon, Pete Myers, Shorty Rogers and Dave Wolpe. The first series, Music from Identified Films, Television Programs and Public Appearances, contains works identified from information included on the music or original accompanying folders. The series is arranged chronologically by date of film, television program or event. Individual songs are listed therein. The second series, Music from Unidentified Sources, contains works whose sources were not able to be identified. This series is arranged alphabetically by work title. Qualifying information (e.g. "play-on") and date of the arrangement are provided wherever possible.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu012018.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2012-08-23T13:41:04</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu010026.2</id>
    <title>Belle Brown Collection </title>
    <updated>2012-09-24T14:21:34</updated>
    <summary>The Belle Brown Collection spans the years 1865-1912 and includes correspondence, newspaper clippings, Miss Brown&#x2019;s contract with the Court Theatre in Weimar, a program of Anton Rubinstein concerts, and iconography related to Miss Brown&#x2019;s vocal training abroad as well as her brief opera career in Weimar. The collection also documents Miss Brown&#x2019;s professional and personal associations with influential European artists.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu010026.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-10-29T17:55:39</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu012020.2</id>
    <title>Marge Champion Collection </title>
    <updated>2012-09-24T14:21:34</updated>
    <summary>The Marge Champion Collection contains materials pertaining to Champion's life and career, and spans the period 1910-2006, with the bulk of the materials falling between 1940 and 1990. </summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu012020.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2012-09-24T14:21:34</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu010008.2</id>
    <title>Martha Graham Collection </title>
    <updated>2012-08-23T13:41:04</updated>
    <summary>The Martha Graham Collection is comprised of materials that document the career of modern dance pioneer Martha Graham and trace the history of the development of her company, the Martha Graham Dance Company, which became the Martha Graham Center of Contemporary Dance, and school, Martha Graham School, later to be called the Martha Graham School of Contemporary Dance. The collection also includes, unprocessed and unavailable for viewing at this time, five linear feet of materials from the Martha Graham School of Contemporary Dance and four linear feet of archival materials relating to Graham&#x2019;s sister, Georgia Graham Sargent. </summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu010008.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:11</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms996005.2</id>
    <title>Henry Harley Arnold Papers</title>
    <updated>2012-08-23T13:41:04</updated>
    <summary>The papers of Henry Harley Arnold (1886-1950) span the years 1903 to 1967, with the bulk of the items concentrated in the years of World War II (1940-1946). The collection is large and contains material on almost all aspects of Arnold's adult life. The most comprehensive documentation, however, covers Arnold's tenure as chief of the United States Army Air Corps (1938-1942), chief of the army air forces (1941-1942), and commanding general of the army air forces (1942-1946). These changes in nomenclature reflect the growth of the military air arm from a small auxiliary of the army in the 1930s to a massive semi-autonomous armed service in World War II which became formally independent of the Army in 1947. Arnold, one of the nation's earliest military pilots, built what became the modern United States Air Force, and his papers are a documentation of that creation.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms996005.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T14:01:29</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu012017.2</id>
    <title>Florence Parr-Gere Papers </title>
    <updated>2012-08-23T13:41:04</updated>
    <summary>The Florence Parr-Gere Papers span a period between 1856-1964 with the majority of materials dating from circa 1900-1943. The papers mainly consist of portraits and other photographs of Parr-Gere that may have been used for publicity purposes. There are also candid outdoor photos and a few family photographs. In addition, there are several inscribed photographs, including one of Percy Grainger. The collection includes 40 of Parr-Gere's songs and piano works published between 1912-1928, as well as a scrapbook compiled by Parr-Gere while attending classes at the American Conservatory at Fontainebleau during the summer of 1921. The scrapbook contains several photographs and autographs accompanied by musical notations from other colleagues, such as Aaron Copland and the Conservatory's founder, Fran&#xE7;ois Casadesus. Also of interest is a small group of five posters publicizing the final two student concerts of September 1921 at Fontainebleau. Other items include Parr-Gere's marriage certificate, a wedding announcement, music publisher brochures listing her compositions, a musical composition inscribed to Parr-Gere, and an 1856 book titled Genealogy of the Geer Family, containing an extensive genealogy of her husband's family.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu012017.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2012-08-23T13:41:04</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu012019.2</id>
    <title>Frederick Loewe Collection</title>
    <updated>2012-08-23T13:41:04</updated>
    <summary>The Frederick Loewe Collection spans 1923-1988, with the bulk of the materials dating between 1945-1975. The Music series contains manuscripts from Loewe's stage and screen musicals, including songs cut from shows. It also contains individual songs not associated with a particular show and songs from less well-known shows. Of particular interest are autograph manuscripts from Loewe's most famous musicals, Brigadoon, Camelot, Gigi, My Fair Lady and Paint Your Wagon. The Miscellaneous Personal Papers series includes correspondence, various writings, programs, and clippings. The Photographs series contains over 500 photographs of Frederick Loewe, his family, friends, and home. The Business Papers series includes manuscript appraisals, records of charitable giving, and correspondence.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu012019.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2012-08-23T13:41:04</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu012004.2</id>
    <title>Modern Music Archives</title>
    <updated>2012-08-23T13:41:04</updated>
    <summary> Modern Music, the quarterly journal of the League of Composers, was published in New York from 1924 to 1946 and edited by Minna Lederman Daniel. Initially the journal was known as The League of Composers' Review. In 1925, the name was changed to Modern Music, although the journal was still published under the auspices of the League. To this day, Modern Music is considered to be one of the most distinguished collections of criticism and scholarship concerning early twentieth-century musical arts. This publication is credited with nurturing an entire generation of composer-critics and for laying the stylistic groundwork for future generations. The roster of contributors includes composers, critics, scholars and artists, many of whom were in the prime of their careers. Exhibited among the twenty-three volumes of this short-lived yet critically-acclaimed journal are the talents of such noteworthy figures as Alban Berg, Aaron Copland, Walter Piston, Virgil Thomson, Paul Rosenfeld, Edwin Denby, Andr&#xE9; Breton, Lincoln Kirstein and Pablo Picasso, among others.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu012004.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2012-04-20T15:44:37</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms009224.2</id>
    <title>Amory Family Papers</title>
    <updated>2012-08-23T13:41:04</updated>
    <summary>The papers of the Amory Family span the years 1697-1882 and consist of correspondence, letterbooks, wills, a petition, financial material, printed matter, and miscellaneous items. The papers are primarily those of Thomas Amory (1682-1728), and his grandson, Thomas Amory (1762-1823), of Boston. </summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms009224.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-10-13T15:18:48</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu010022.2</id>
    <title>Tams-Witmark Collection</title>
    <updated>2012-08-23T13:41:04</updated>
    <summary>The Tams-Witmark Library holdings reflect what was being performed in the United States during the late nineteenth and early twentieth centuries. The scope of the collection ranges from eighteenth century operas of Handel and Gl&#xFC;ck to a musical by George M. Cohan. The bulk of the materials are nineteenth century operas and operettas, the majority in full score, but there are also instrumental parts, particularly for those works from the latter half of the nineteenth century. Most of the scores have been annotated with cuts and performance markings, and some, such as Bizet's Carmen, Auber's Fra Diavolo, and Gounod's Romeo et Juliette, feature reduced or non-standard orchestrations.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu010022.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-10-13T15:16:00</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mbrsrs/eadmbrs.rs011001.2</id>
    <title>Emile Berliner Collection </title>
    <updated>2012-08-23T13:41:04</updated>
    <summary>The Emile Berliner Collection includes disc recordings, textual materials, photographs, artifacts, and a film. The textual materials consist of more than 1,000 items including correspondence, notes and papers, books, addresses, newspaper and magazine articles, catalogs, diaries and journals, pamphlets, patents, and scrapbooks dealing with Berliner's work and personal life, as well as his philanthropic endeavors. The photographs are both studio portraits and informal snapshots of Berliner, his family, his associates, and his inventions. Artifacts include telephone, gramophone, and laboratory equipment, along with several acoustic panel pieces and material samples.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmbrs.rs011001.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-10-25T14:51:39</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu012010.2</id>
    <title>Burt Boyar Collection of Sammy Davis, Jr. Biographical Materials </title>
    <updated>2012-08-23T13:41:04</updated>
    <summary>The Burt Boyar Collection of Sammy Davis, Jr. Biographical Materials consists of drafts, galleys and page proofs for the books Yes I Can: The Story of Sammy Davis, Jr. and Sammy: An Autobiography, thirty-five cassette tapes with interviews conducted by Boyar and his wife Jane for their book Why Me?: The Sammy Davis, Jr. Story, and digital media and text files of Davis appearances, recordings and interviews stored on a portable hard drive. These materials span the years 1954 to 2000 with the majority dating from 1965 to 1988.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu012010.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2012-08-23T13:41:04</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu009006.2</id>
    <title>Minna Lederman Daniel Collection </title>
    <updated>2012-08-23T13:41:04</updated>
    <summary>The Minna Lederman Daniel Collection consists of the papers of this noted writer and editor. The date span of the collection is from 1896-1993, with the bulk of the materials dating from the 1960s to the early 1990s. The collection includes correspondence, writings, financial and legal papers, programs, periodicals, clippings, and photographs.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu009006.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:09</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu009011.2</id>
    <title>Federal Music Project Collection</title>
    <updated>2012-08-23T13:41:04</updated>
    <summary>The Federal Music Project Collection consists of agency reports, programs, catalogs, index cards, lists, correspondence, questionnaires, clippings, some music scores and parts, a few writings and the papers of George Allen Foster, regional director for New York and New England. The George Allen Foster Collection consists of correspondence, photographs, programs, clippings and reports. These materials span the years from 1935 to 1948, with the bulk of the materials dating from 1936 to 1941. The collection is arranged into nine series: Reports, Music Library, Music and Other Performing Media, Composer&#x2019;s Index, Bio-Bibliographical Index of Musicians, Writings, Programs, Clippings and the George Allen Foster Collection. </summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu009011.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:57</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu012016.2</id>
    <title>Robert Whitehead Papers </title>
    <updated>2012-08-23T13:41:04</updated>
    <summary>The Robert Whitehead Papers span the period 1947-2002, with the majority of materials dating from 1950-1996. They include production files, correspondence, business papers, published and unpublished writings, photographs, costume and set renderings, programs and promotional materials, scripts, and biographical materials.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu012016.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2012-07-20T15:01:50</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu998001.2</id>
    <title>Leonard Bernstein Collection</title>
    <updated>2012-07-20T15:01:50</updated>
    <summary>The Leonard Bernstein Collection is as exceptional a collection as its namesake would suggest. Bernstein, one of the most prominent figures in twentieth century American classical music, made his impact as a conductor, composer of classical and theater music, and as an educator through his books, conducting students at Tanglewood, and, especially, his various televised lecture series that helped define the potentials of that medium.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu998001.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T14:04:41</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu010001.2</id>
    <title>Serge Grigoriev/Ballets Russes Archive </title>
    <updated>2012-07-20T15:01:50</updated>
    <summary>The Serge Grigoriev/Ballets Russes Archive is comprised of materials that document Serge Grigoriev&#x2019;s career as a dancer and as r&#xE9;gisseur (rehearsal director) for the Ballets Russes de Serge Diaghilev (1909-1929). Grigoriev served in the same capacity for the Ballets Russes de Colonel W. de Basil (1932-1952). The manuscripts, photographs, and other documents that are included in this Archive provide one of the richest collections of information on these two dance companies available anywhere.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu010001.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:09</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mbrsrs/eadmbrs.rs000001.2</id>
    <title>NBC: A Finding Aid to the National Broadcasting Company History Files at the Library of Congress, Motion Picture, Broadcasting and Recorded Sound Division</title>
    <updated>2012-07-20T15:01:50</updated>
    <summary>This finding aid documents the National Broadcasting Company History Files which is one of the eleven collections that comprise the NBC Archives at the Library of Congress. The NBC Archives document the history of the organization and its broadcast programming, and the history of the radio and television industries. The eleven collections within the NBC Archives at the Library of Congress include: organizational records of NBC, and the radio stations WEAF and WJZ; indexes to radio and television programming and artists; log books of broadcasts; sound recordings of radio broadcasts; and kinescopes of television broadcasts. </summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmbrs.rs000001.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:24</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu012014.2</id>
    <title>Hugo Leichtentritt Papers</title>
    <updated>2012-07-20T15:01:50</updated>
    <summary>The Hugo Leichtentritt Papers consist of music manuscripts, correspondence, clippings, programs, scrapbooks, and writings on music history, criticism, and theory. The collection spans the period 1888 to 1972, with the bulk of the materials dating from 1890 to the 1933.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu012014.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2012-07-20T15:01:50</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu012013.2</id>
    <title>Victor Herbert Collection</title>
    <updated>2012-07-20T15:01:50</updated>
    <summary>The Victor Herbert Collection chiefly consists of manuscripts (full and reduced scores, orchestral parts, and sketches) of the theater works of Victor Herbert, including his light operas such as Babes in Toyland, The Red Mill and Naughty Marietta. In addition to his operettas and operas, items include one silent film score, overtures for several feature films, selections written for a number of productions by the Lambs&#x2019; Club, and selections from several Broadway revues. In addition, the collection includes manuscripts for most of Herbert&#x2019;s large-scale symphonic works, chamber pieces, solo songs and choral compositions.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu012013.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2012-07-20T15:01:50</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu011019.2</id>
    <title>Laurence Picken Papers </title>
    <updated>2012-07-20T15:01:50</updated>
    <summary>The Laurence Picken Papers span the period 1900-2001 with the majority of materials dating from 1936-1999. The materials include project files, research materials, business and personal correspondence, published and unpublished writings, scores of Picken's own compositions, and photographs.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu011019.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-11-18T20:00:42</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu010019.2</id>
    <title>George Antheil Correspondence to Stanley Hart </title>
    <updated>2012-06-21T13:25:17</updated>
    <summary>The George Antheil Correspondence to Stanley Hart spans the period 1919-1931, with the majority of materials dating from 1922-1923. Included are letters, postcards, and telegrams from Antheil to Hart, in addition to several letters to Antheil from Mary Hollister, Ethel Leginska, and Annette Williams, and three letters from unidentified authors to Hart. The letters chronicle Antheil&#x2019;s personal and professional exploits during his European tour, which began in 1922. In addition to commentary on cities he visited, concerts he performed, and musical pieces he was working on, Antheil also confided in Hart details of his personal relationships. The correspondence offers a unique perspective on the life of this influential futurist composer and his acquaintances. </summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu010019.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:14</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu010018.2</id>
    <title>George Antheil Correspondence with Mary Louise Curtis Bok </title>
    <updated>2012-06-21T13:25:17</updated>
    <summary>The George Antheil Correspondence with Mary Louise Curtis Bok spans the period 1921-1940. The primary series consists chiefly of letters and telegrams between the composer and his patron. Correspondence between Bok and others regarding Antheil, namely Ezra Pound, Donald S. Friede, and Constantin von Sternberg, is arranged alphabetically by correspondent. Clippings and other enclosures are scattered among these materials. Additional items of note include a letter from Pound to Antheil and a telegram from Igor Stravinsky to the composer.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu010018.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:14</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu010010.2</id>
    <title>Sidney Robertson Cowell Collection </title>
    <updated>2012-06-21T13:25:17</updated>
    <summary>The Sidney Robertson Cowell Collection, numbering more than 5,000 items, contains material from her work as a folk song collector and ethnographer; voluminous correspondence to her family, friends and colleagues--many of whom are prominent figures in 20th century American music--published and unpublished essays, reviews, and articles; biographical narratives; instructional materials from various stints as a music teacher, and an extensive subject file. The collection contains a great amount of information on Sidney Robertson Cowell&#x2019;s husband, modernist composer Henry Cowell, including material pertaining to their marriage, writings by and about him, material dealing with his professional relationships with other notables in the music world, and documents concerning his musical legacy, which was carefully nurtured by Sidney Robertson Cowell.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu010010.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:59</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu012008.2</id>
    <title>Irving Berlin Collection </title>
    <updated>2012-06-21T13:25:17</updated>
    <summary>The Irving Berlin Collection, spanning the years 1895-1990 with the bulk of the material dating from 1915-1990, documents the life and work of one of the twentieth century's most legendary American musical figures. While the collection provides a comprehensive record of Berlin's life as a composer, lyricist, publisher and theater owner, it also serves as a resource for the study of American popular music. Berlin wrote more than 1,200 songs, including such standards as "White Christmas," "There's No Business Like Show Business," and "God Bless America," that gave a musical voice to much of the American experience of the twentieth century. A large part of his reputation also justifiably rests on his great ballads of the 1920s and 1930s, including "Always," "Cheek to Cheek," "How Deep Is the Ocean (How High Is the Sky)," "Let's Face the Music and Dance," and "What'll I Do." The materials in the Irving Berlin Collection document additional aspects of Berlin's career, such as music publishing, theater ownership, and founding membership in the American Society of Composers, Authors, and Publishers. The breadth of his activity coupled with his longevity (he died at age 101) produced one of the largest collections in the custody of the Library of Congress Music Division.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu012008.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2012-06-21T13:25:17</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.rbc/eadrbc.rb999001.2</id>
    <title>King Lear Archive</title>
    <updated>2012-06-21T13:25:17</updated>
    <summary>The collection consists of woodcuts, drawings, correspondence, proofs, book designers' mockups, and woodblocks for an edition of Shakespeare's The Tragedie of King Lear published by Theodore Press in 1986 with illustrations by Claire Van Vliet. The publication is based on the 1623 first folio text of the play, and was produced in a limited edition of 160 copies, each signed by Claire Van Vliet. The woodcuts include several proofs of each illustration, most of which are images of characters in the drama. The collection also includes preliminary pencil drawings for each of the woodcuts, as well as a complete set of the original wood blocks. Correspondence relating to all aspects of the project during 1985 and 1986 is chiefly by Claire Van Vliet, founder of Janus Press, and Michael Alpert, owner of Theodore Press. The collection was assembled and arranged by Claire Van Vliet.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadrbc.rb999001.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:18</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu010014.2</id>
    <title>George and Ira Gershwin Collection </title>
    <updated>2012-06-21T13:25:17</updated>
    <summary>The materials in the George and Ira Gershwin Collection document many aspects of the lives and careers of composer George Gershwin (1898-1937) and his lyricist brother, Ira Gershwin (1896-1983). They span the years 1895-2008, with the bulk of the material dating from 1920 to 1960.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu010014.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:12</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/eadafc.af010001.2</id>
    <title>Mary Sheppard Burton Collection</title>
    <updated>2012-06-21T13:25:17</updated>
    <summary>The collection consists of twelve rugs hooked with hand-dyed wool on 12-thread-count linen titled the Tell Me &#x2018;Bout Series created by Mary Sheppard Burton from Germantown, Maryland. The rugs, which were created between 1993 and 2005, depict stories of rural life and historical events experienced by different members of Burton&#x2019;s family. These stories, some of which have been passed down for generations, include scenes of life on the Chesapeake Bay and surrounding areas in Maryland. Burton retold this family history as bedtime stories for her four children. She designed and made this series of hooked rugs which artistically retold the stories. Color photographs of Mary Sheppard Burton with American Folklife Center director Peggy A. Bulger were taken by David A. Taylor in 2006. Burton was interviewed at her home by Theadocia Austen and Carl Lindahl, circa 2001. During the interview Burton gave a tour of her house, describing the history of the various rooms and the many pieces of art on display throughout her house.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadafc.af010001.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-03-04T15:34:44</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mbrsrs/eadmbrs.rs010002.2</id>
    <title> Louisiana Hayride Collection</title>
    <updated>2012-06-21T13:25:17</updated>
    <summary>The collection predominantly covers early radio and television history in Shreveport, Louisiana; KWKH radio in the W.K. Henderson era; and the Louisiana Hayride years at KWKH radio. The Early Shreveport Radio and Television series provides special emphasis on the careers of Paul Carriger and William E. Antony (the latter was head engineer in the early days of WGAQ/KWKH). This is documented in ephemera, radio licenses, and published articles.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmbrs.rs010002.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-09-22T16:17:42</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mbrsrs/eadmbrs.rs010001.2</id>
    <title>Record Industry Publicity Collection</title>
    <updated>2012-06-21T13:25:17</updated>
    <summary>The collection includes press releases, disc catalogs, scripts from radio programs, monthly publications about new record releases, and promotional posters. The materials were originally created to promote recordings issued by labels such as Capitol, Columbia, Decca, and RCA Victor; broadcasters such as NBC; and performance rights organizations such as ASCAP and BMI. </summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmbrs.rs010001.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-10-13T15:16:16</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.rbc/eadrbc.rb998001.2</id>
    <title>The Janus Press Archive</title>
    <updated>2012-06-21T13:25:17</updated>
    <summary>The Janus Press Archive contains material relating to the production of books, posters and broadsides, and printed ephemera bearing the Janus Press imprint, as well as other projects carried out with the assistance of its founder Claire Van Vliet, covering the period from 1955 to the present.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadrbc.rb998001.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:18</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu012011.2</id>
    <title>Edward Jablonski Papers </title>
    <updated>2012-06-21T13:25:17</updated>
    <summary>The Edward Jablonski Papers span the period of 1942-2003, with the majority of the materials dating from 1950-2000. The collection includes book project materials, articles, liner notes, drafts, and related correspondence and business papers. All research, correspondence, and business papers pertaining to a given project are filed with its draft materials.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu012011.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2012-06-21T13:25:17</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/eadafc.af012001.2</id>
    <title>Maine Acadian Cultural Survey Collection </title>
    <updated>2012-06-21T13:25:17</updated>
    <summary>The Maine Acadian Cultural Survey Project was conducted in 1991 as a joint project of the American Folklife Center and the North Atlantic Regional Office of the National Park Service. In 1990 the U.S. Congress passed the Maine Acadian Culture Preservation Act (P.L.101-543), mandating that a study of Acadian culture in Maine be conducted for the purpose of providing data to be used in planning an Acadian Cultural Center in Maine. As a result of this act, the Park Service invited the Center to join them in undertaking such a study. The Maine Acadian Cultural Survey Project is the fifth major collaborative project between the Park Service and the Center, and the design and execution of the project were largely based on knowledge gained through earlier projects. </summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadafc.af012001.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2012-05-21T09:02:48</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu003010.2</id>
    <title>George and B&#xF6;ske Antheil Papers </title>
    <updated>2012-06-21T13:25:17</updated>
    <summary>The George and B&#xF6;ske Antheil Papers span the period 1875-1984, with the majority of materials dating from 1920-1958. They include holograph music manuscripts, printed music, published and unpublished writings, business and personal correspondence, subject files, photographs, programs and promotional materials, scrapbooks, artwork, biographical materials, and memorabilia.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu003010.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:15</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu012005.2</id>
    <title>Herbert L. Kirk Collection </title>
    <updated>2012-05-21T09:02:48</updated>
    <summary>Herbert L. Kirk is best known in the field of musicology as the author of Pablo Casals, a Biography (Holt, Rinehart and Winston, 1974), the authorized biography of Pablo Casals. The bulk of the material in the Kirk collection is related to this book and includes various drafts of the work and material gathered in researching the subject.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu012005.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2012-05-21T09:02:48</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu011018.2</id>
    <title>Nikolay Karlovich Medtner Papers </title>
    <updated>2012-05-21T09:02:48</updated>
    <summary> The Nikolay Karlovich Medtner Papers contain letters, programs, clippings, photographs, scores, books, realia, and other items related to Medtner's family life and career as a concert pianist. These materials date from 1826-1954, with the majority dating from 1914-1954. The Correspondence series takes up nearly half the collection and consists of family and general correspondence written between 1914 and 1954, containing over 1,900 letters in Russian, German, English, and French. Family correspondence (1914-1936) consists of approximately 500 letters by Nikolay and/or wife Anna to &#x116;mili&#x12D; Karlovich Metner with over 400 letters in reply. The general correspondence (1921-1954) contains significant letters and transcripts to and from Sergei and Nataliia Rachmaninoff, Leon and Olga Conus, Sofiia Aleksandrovna Satina, Konstantin Klimov, Madeleine Lalibert&#xE9; (Mrs. Albert Lalibert&#xE9;), Bernard and Cecile Pinsonneault, Abb&#xE9; J.G. Turcotte, and smaller holdings of letters by other musicians and admirers. This series also contains condolence letters sent to Anna upon Nikolay&#x2019;s death and a large quantity of unidentified letters.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu011018.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-10-25T14:51:38</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/eadafc.af011019.2</id>
    <title>1992 Neptune Plaza Concert Series Collection</title>
    <updated>2012-05-21T09:02:48</updated>
    <summary>The 1992 Neptune Plaza Concert Series Collection consists of manuscript and print materials, sound recordings, graphic materials, and moving images that document the 1992 concert series sponsored by the American Folklife Center. The annual series, which began in 1977, features the presentation of folk traditions from many cultures. The concerts take place on the Neptune Plaza at the front of the Jefferson Building of the Library of Congress between April and September. Adverse weather conditions sometimes force the concerts indoors. </summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadafc.af011019.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2012-02-16T13:15:26</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu012009.2</id>
    <title>Anita O'Day Papers </title>
    <updated>2012-05-21T09:02:48</updated>
    <summary>The Anita O'Day Papers span from 1937 to 2004 with the majority of the materials dating from the 1940s to the 1970s. The collection primarily consists of manuscript scores, lead sheets, parts, and annotated sheet music for arrangements of popular songs and jazz standards performed by O'Day throughout her career. Although much fewer in number than the lead sheets, the full scores and parts reflect her work with many prominent arrangers, including Buddy Bregman, Joe Castro, Russell Garcia, Bill Holman, Quincy Jones, Norman "Tiny" Kahn, Billy May, Roger Neumann, and Marty Paich. The collection also includes a small assortment of scrapbooks, photographs, correspondence, clippings, honors and awards, posters, and publicity materials. Digitized images of the scrapbooks are available.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu012009.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2012-05-21T09:02:48</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu003002.2</id>
    <title>Fritz Kreisler Collection</title>
    <updated>2012-05-21T09:02:48</updated>
    <summary>Fritz Kreisler is known predominantly for his artistry as a violinist, particularly in performances of his own transcriptions and cadenzas, but he is also worthy of note as a composer. More than fifty of Kreisler's original compositions are represented in this collection, in sketch, manuscript, or printed form. Holographs of some of Kreisler's most popular compositions, such as Caprice viennois, Liebesfreud, and the Viennese rhapsodic fantasietta, are complemented by his manuscripts of less well-known works, including Drei Nachtges&#xE4;nge (with poetry by Eichendorff) and his Song, op. 7, for violin and piano. Included among the holographs are several works of the Klassische Manuskripte series, a set of 14 pieces for violin and piano that were thought to be Kreisler's transcriptions of classical works until 1935, when it was revealed that they were his original compositions. Kreisler's Viennese light opera Sissy (1932) is also represented in the collection, both by holograph full scores of most of its individual numbers and by a complete printed vocal score.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu003002.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:17</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms011151.2</id>
    <title> American Scholar Records </title>
    <updated>2012-05-21T09:02:48</updated>
    <summary>The American Scholar is a quarterly magazine of public affairs, literature, science, history, and culture published by the Phi Beta Kappa Society since 1932. Its records span the years 1926-2006, with the bulk of the material concentrated in the period between 1944 and 2005. The collection is arranged in three parts. </summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms011151.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-11-18T20:01:08</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu012006.2</id>
    <title>Winston Sharples Music Manuscripts </title>
    <updated>2012-05-21T09:02:48</updated>
    <summary>The Winston Sharples Music Manuscripts spans a period between 1943 and 1968, roughly corresponding to the years Sharples was active as principal composer for Paramount's animation production branch, Famous Studios. During this twenty-five year period, Sharples composed music for almost 700 animated short films while also serving as music director of Paramount's live action Pacemaker short films, and also contributing to other Paramount film series such as Headliner, Musical Parade, and Paramount News, and longer documentaries - some produced by other companies.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu012006.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2012-05-21T09:02:48</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu012007.2</id>
    <title>Danny Kaye and Sylvia Fine Collection </title>
    <updated>2012-05-21T09:02:48</updated>
    <summary>The Danny Kaye and Sylvia Fine Collection documents the life and work of actor, singer, dancer and comedian Danny Kaye and his wife, lyricist, composer, writer, lecturer and producer Sylvia Fine. It includes printed and manuscript music, scripts, correspondence, business and financial papers, promotional and publicity materials, photographs, programs, posters, awards, and realia. </summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu012007.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2012-05-21T09:02:48</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mbrsrs/eadmbrs.rs011002.2</id>
    <title>Tony Schwartz Collection</title>
    <updated>2012-05-21T09:02:48</updated>
    <summary>The Tony Schwartz Collection consists of multiple formats of material containing the products of his work as a media consultant, audio documentarian, author, radio producer, media theorist, and educator, as well as the research, consultation, preparation and editing, testing, and revision that led to his published textual and media-based works. Also included are published writings and videos about Schwartz, correspondence with colleagues and clients, and extensive files about people, organizations, and topics that interested Schwartz during his long and productive career.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmbrs.rs011002.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2012-04-20T15:44:37</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu995001.2</id>
    <title>Federal Theatre Project Collection</title>
    <updated>2012-04-20T15:44:37</updated>
    <summary>The Federal Theatre Project (FTP), an agency of the WPA from 1935 to 1939, provided work for thousands of unemployed persons in the theatrical profession. The project was an experiment which mirrored life in the Depression; depicted economic, political, and social problems; developed new audiences; provided opportunities for minorities; and laid the groundwork for much innovation in the theater. It was the first arts endeavor to be supported on a extensive scale by the U.S. government.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu995001.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:43</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms010030.2</id>
    <title>Frank Maxwell Andrews Papers</title>
    <updated>2012-04-20T15:44:37</updated>
    <summary>The papers of Frank Maxwell Andrews (1884-1943) span the years 1920-1943, with the bulk of the material from 1935 to 1942. The collection consists of family correspondence, general correspondence, and copies of official correspondence; financial records; reports and memoranda; manuscript and near-print copies of speeches and articles; memorabilia; newspaper clippings; a few other printed items ; and additional material, mostly correspondence. Except for Andrews&#x2019;s military service record (201 File) and flight record, which begin in 1920 and 1921 respectively, there are no materials dated before 1924. There are almost no papers dated after November 1942 when Andrews left the Caribbean Defense Command for the Middle East at Cairo.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms010030.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-10-29T17:56:39</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu005003.2</id>
    <title>Lester Horton Dance Theater Collection</title>
    <updated>2012-04-20T15:44:37</updated>
    <summary>The Lester Horton Dance Theater Collection is a collection of multi-format materials documenting the work of dancer-teacher-choreographer Lester Horton as well as the workings of a modern dance company in California. The collection consists of correspondence, writings, publicity and production materials, programs, costume and set designs, news clippings, teaching materials, music, photographs, business papers, scrapbooks, drawings, publications, and audiovisual materials (the audiovisual materials were transferred to the Motion Picture, Broadcasting and Recorded Sound Division of the Library of Congress). The collection spans the years 1926 to 1996, with the bulk of the materials dated from the 1940s through the 1950s. Since Horton's private life was intertwined with his professional one, the collection includes information on both. Individuals represented include Alvin Ailey, William Bowne, Merce Cunningham, Carmen De Lavallade, Frank Eng, Lelia Goldoni, Judith Hamilton, Michio It&#x14D;, Bella Lewitzky, Margaret Lloyd, Don Martin, Joyce Trisler, James Truitte, and Larry Warren.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu005003.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:42</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mbrsrs/eadmbrs.rs009001.2</id>
    <title>Arch Oboler Collection</title>
    <updated>2012-04-20T15:44:37</updated>
    <summary>Arch Oboler&#x2019;s career as author, radio and stage playwright and director, and movie script writer and director spanned some sixty years, from the late 1920s to the 1980s. Included in his papers is his accumulation of correspondence, legal, business, and personal files, and manuscript and other materials related to his vast creative output in different media.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmbrs.rs009001.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2012-01-19T20:07:04</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms010154.2</id>
    <title>Goodman Ace Papers</title>
    <updated>2012-04-20T15:44:37</updated>
    <summary>The papers of Goodman Ace (1899-1982) span the years 1931-1972, with the bulk of the material dating from 1931 to 1967. They consist primarily of bound volumes containing approximately two thousand scripts for radio and television programs. Goodman Ace was a comic writer who wrote for radio in the 1930s and 1940s and for television in the 1950s and 1960s. Ace and his wife Jane starred in a long-running network radio program, &#x201C;Easy Aces,&#x201D; which Goodman Ace wrote, produced, and directed. He later wrote for radio and television programs featuring such performers as Tallulah Bankhead, Milton Berle, Perry Como, and Danny Kaye. At one point, Ace was the highest paid writer in television. The Goodman Ace Papers contain scripts for most of the programs for which he wrote. Some scripts contain hand-written annotations. The papers are organized in three series: Radio Scripts, Television Scripts, and Miscellany.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms010154.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-10-13T15:19:17</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu003001.2</id>
    <title>John Alden Carpenter Collection</title>
    <updated>2012-04-20T15:44:37</updated>
    <summary>The John Alden Carpenter Collection spans the years 1891 to 1961 and contains music materials, correspondence, writings, photographs and artwork, certificates and honors, programs, clippings and scrapbooks. The bulk of the collection consists of musical materials, primarily holograph manuscripts of Carpenter's songs, orchestral pieces, and dramatic works. The holograph manuscripts of Carpenter's songs are perhaps the most remarkable feature of the collection, as they include not only his better-known works but also many that have never been published. Notable among these are numerous unpublished youthful works, such as "Brother," "My Red Hair," and "My Horror," as well as several songs from the cycles Gitanjali and Water-Colors. Carpenter's chamber and orchestral works are well represented also. For many works that Carpenter later arranged or revised, the collection contains both the original and at least one revision. The materials for Birthday of the Infanta, for example, consist of three full scores, including both the 1918 original and a revised version from 1949, as well as holograph changes to the 1949 revision; a holograph arrangement for piano, 4 hands (1938); the composer's reduction of the first movement vocalise, with harp and piano accompaniment; and numerous sketches. A number of the printed scores of Carpenter's music in the collection feature holograph annotations or alterations.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu003001.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:15</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms009139.2</id>
    <title>Chester Alan Arthur Papers</title>
    <updated>2012-04-20T15:44:37</updated>
    <summary> Series 4, the Addition to the Arthur Papers, spans the period 1846-1960 and is arranged in four subseries: Correspondence, Financial Papers, Scrapbooks, and Miscellany.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms009139.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T14:00:34</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms010127.2</id>
    <title>Nelson W. Aldrich Papers</title>
    <updated>2012-04-20T15:44:37</updated>
    <summary>The papers of Nelson Wilmarth Aldrich (1841-1915) span the years 1777-1930, with the bulk of the material concentrated in 1879-1915. The collection is composed primarily of correspondence, printed matter, and material relating to tariff legislation and the National Monetary Commission, supplemented by diaries, notebooks, speeches, research notes, serial publications, financial records, and miscellaneous items. </summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms010127.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T14:00:32</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu011009.2</id>
    <title>Billy Taylor Papers </title>
    <updated>2012-04-20T15:44:37</updated>
    <summary>The Billy Taylor Collection represents a comprehensive resource for the study of jazz history, performance, and pedagogy. Dr. Taylor was more than a renowned jazz pianist and composer, he was also an educator who lectured extensively at colleges and universities nationwide, and authored several books on jazz history, theory and appreciation. The collection, which spans the years 1942-2004, documents the depth and breadth of Taylor&#x2019;s multifaceted career as a musician, composer, writer, host, and jazz ambassador. Throughout his career, Taylor worked tirelessly as an advocate for jazz and to produce programs that promoted jazz as &#x201C;America&#x2019;s classical music.&#x201D; </summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu011009.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-08-19T16:21:19</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu011002.2</id>
    <title>Dexter Gordon Collection </title>
    <updated>2012-04-20T15:44:37</updated>
    <summary>Most of the materials in the Dexter Gordon Collection were collected by Dexter Gordon&#x2019;s wife, Maxine Gordon, from the late 1970s until Dexter Gordon&#x2019;s death in 1990. The materials date from the early 1940s to 1996, with the bulk falling between 1960 and 1988. Of particular interest in the Biographical Materials series is an unfinished autobiography entitled &#x201C;The Saga of Society Red,&#x201D; a project which Gordon began in 1983. It is composed of a number of interrelated vignettes which recount various incidents in Gordon&#x2019;s life and career. It also deals with his relationships with a number of jazz musicians, including Count Basie, Lionel Hampton, and Lester Young; his European tours; and meetings with celebrities.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu011002.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-04-25T17:56:05</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms011056.2</id>
    <title>Carl W. Ackerman Papers</title>
    <updated>2012-04-20T15:44:37</updated>
    <summary>The papers of Carl William Ackerman (1890-1970) span the years 1833-1970, with the bulk of the material concentrated in 1931-1956 when he was dean of the School of Journalism and Graduate School of Journalism at Columbia University. The collection constitutes an important source for the history of twentieth-century journalism as well as for some of the public questions in which he took an interest, most notably freedom of the press and journalism education. The papers also include documentation of Ackerman's activities as a news correspondent during and after World War I, the scene of which ranged from Germany in 1915-1917, to Siberia in 1918, to American labor unrest in 1919, to the Irish rebellion in 1920-1921. In addition, there are papers concerning his activities as a public relations consultant from 1921 to 1927. The collection consists of Diaries; Family Papers; General Correspondence; Subject File, Speech, Article and Book File; Miscellany; Oversize; and Classified series.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms011056.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-06-21T11:34:57</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu010029.2</id>
    <title>Roy Harris Papers </title>
    <updated>2012-04-20T15:44:37</updated>
    <summary>The Roy Harris Papers span the period 1893-1998, with the majority of the materials dating from 1933-1979. Included are music manuscripts, published and unpublished writings, correspondence, business papers, financial and legal documents, photographs, scrapbooks, work files, programs, posters, clippings, and biographical materials.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu010029.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-12-20T20:06:55</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms009106.2</id>
    <title> Amos 'n' Andy Radio Program Scripts</title>
    <updated>2012-04-20T15:44:37</updated>
    <summary>The scripts of the Amos &#x2018;n Andy radio program consist of scripts submitted to the Library of Congress Copyright Office between 1928 and 1937 and organized and filmed chronologically by date of broadcast.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms009106.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T14:01:56</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms009315.2</id>
    <title>Charles McLean Andrews Collection Concerning Colonial History</title>
    <updated>2012-03-28T12:56:41</updated>
    <summary>The Charles McLean Andrews Collection Concerning Colonial History consists of transcripts of manuscripts in various repositories in England and spans the years 1623-1800. The materials were accumulated by Andrews for use in his writings on American colonial history and cover admiralty courts and cases, trade, and political matters. Andrews authored Lists of Transcript from the British Museum and the Bodleian Library . . . (Washington, D.C.: Carnegie Institution of Washington, 1908) that lists the transcripts acquired by the Library of Congress.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms009315.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T14:02:00</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/eadafc.af006003.2</id>
    <title> American Folk Blues Festival Photograph Collection, 1962-1965 </title>
    <updated>2012-03-28T12:56:41</updated>
    <summary>The 68 digital prints in this collection document the musicians who participated in the American Folk Blues Festival from 1962 to 1965. The American Folk Blues Festival brought American blues musicians to Europe for live concerts and studio performances between 1962 and 1982. Promoted by German blues enthusiasts, Horst Lippmann and Fritz Rau, the festival influenced the musical landscape of Europe as it exposed young musicians such as Mick Jagger, Keith Richards, and Jimmy Page to blues music. Stephanie Wiesand usually photographed the musicians during television tapings that took place at S&#xFC;dwestfunk, a German television and radio station in Baden-Baden, Germany.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadafc.af006003.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:56</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/eadafc.af005004.2</id>
    <title>Robert Sonkin Alabama and New Jersey Collection</title>
    <updated>2012-03-28T12:56:41</updated>
    <summary>The collection consists of documentation from Robert Sonkin's field recording trip to Shell Pile, near Port Norris, New Jersey, and from there to Gee's Bend and other locations in Alabama in June-July 1941. Sonkin recorded two discs of African American quartets performing gospel music in Shell Pile, June 25, 1941. His field notes also describe the African American community of Shell Pile, named for the oyster shucking industry established there near Port Norris, N.J. Forty-nine of the sixty-three discs were made in various locations in Gee's Bend, Alabama, and include prayer meetings, sermons, gospel music, spirituals, hymns, jubilee quartet singing, blues, children's songs, recitations and conversations. These discussions cover health and home remedies, the Gee's Bend school, and the Farm Security Administration's (FSA) Gee's Bend study. Sonkin also recorded ten discs in other areas in Alabama, including gospel quartet music in Bessemer, Alabama; interviews in Camden and Palmerdale, Alabama; and gospel music in Rehoboth and Greensboro, Alabama. Narratives by two former slaves, Isom Moseley and Alice Gaston, were recorded on July 22, 1941. </summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadafc.af005004.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:57</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms009330.2</id>
    <title>Charles Julius Allen and Grace Elizabeth Allen Papers</title>
    <updated>2012-03-28T12:56:41</updated>
    <summary>The papers of Charles Julius Allen (1840-1915) and Grace Elizabeth Allen (1886-1976), father and daughter, span the years 1865-1976 and consist of correspondence, diaries, family histories, personal reminiscences, notes, clippings, and printed matter.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms009330.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-12-20T20:07:11</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/eadafc.af006005.2</id>
    <title>Fletcher Collins Jr. Collection </title>
    <updated>2012-03-28T12:56:41</updated>
    <summary>The manuscript materials in this collection reflect Collins's Anglo-American folk music collecting activities from 1935 to 1944. Collins undertook numerous projects, including a proposed song book titled A Southern Songster and a radio series on WBIG, Greensboro, N.C. Administrative papers and correspondence for these and other projects are included among the manuscript materials.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadafc.af006005.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:51</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms009331.2</id>
    <title>American Foreign Service Association Records</title>
    <updated>2012-03-28T12:56:41</updated>
    <summary>The records of the American Foreign Service Association span the years 1940-1964 and consist of editorial correspondence, articles, memoranda, editorials, essays, photographs, newspaper clippings, and printed matter pertaining to the publication of the American Foreign Service Journal issued in Washington, D.C., by the American Foreign Service Association, also known as the Foreign Service Association. </summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms009331.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-12-20T20:07:08</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms011069.2</id>
    <title>Am-Rus Literary Agency Records</title>
    <updated>2012-03-28T12:56:41</updated>
    <summary>The records of the Am-Rus Literary Agency span the years 1927-1990, with the bulk of the material dating from 1945 to 1990. Through its affiliation with the Copyright Agency of the USSR (VAAP), the Am-Rus agency represented Soviet authors in negotiations with publishers and theatrical producers in the United States. Written in English and Russian, the records include correspondence, contracts, royalty statements, news clippings, printed matter, writings, and photographs. The collection has been organized in two series: Author File and Miscellany. </summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms011069.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-08-19T16:21:39</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms010273.2</id>
    <title>American Association of University Women Records</title>
    <updated>2012-03-28T12:56:41</updated>
    <summary>The records of the American Association of University Women contain the files of an extensive research project undertaken by the organization's Arts Resource Center on the history and development of the arts in America. The surveys were conducted by the association's branches in various cities and towns and in various locations. While the collection spans the years 1937-1946, the project was carried out primarily from 1937 to 1938.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms010273.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-03-25T13:30:57</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/eadafc.af011004.2</id>
    <title> Paul Bowles Moroccan Music Collection</title>
    <updated>2012-03-28T12:56:41</updated>
    <summary>The collection includes dance music, secular music, music for Ramadan and other Islamic rites, and music for animistic rituals. Berber and Arab music predominates, and Sephardic liturgical music and folk songs are included. Dance was often integral to the music events. Field notes and correspondence describe the recording events (including dance) and circumstances of the project. Manuscripts in English. Sound recordings in Berber languages, Arabic, and Hebrew.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadafc.af011004.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2012-03-28T12:56:41</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms010048.2</id>
    <title>Nathan Appleton Papers</title>
    <updated>2012-03-28T12:56:41</updated>
    <summary>The papers of Nathan Appleton (1843-1906) span the period 1850-1904, with the bulk concentrated in the years 1876-1902. The collection consists largely of an autobiography, letters, newspaper articles, and other printed matter mostly relating to Appleton's connections with French attempts to construct a Panamanian canal and to his support of free trade. </summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms010048.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-01-28T18:15:05</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms009329.2</id>
    <title>American Colonization Society Records</title>
    <updated>2012-03-28T12:56:41</updated>
    <summary>The records of the American Colonization Society span the years 1792-1964, with the bulk of the material concentrated in the period 1823-1912. The records include a variety of material, but in terms of content and physical size the various correspondence series predominate. The society's major interests and activities changed in emphasis during its long history, and this change is reflected in the voluminous correspondence, which ranges in subject from routine administrative and financial matters to the problems of slavery, the status of slaves and freedmen in society, and the advantages and disadvantages of emigration and colonization. The collection is organized in seven series: Incoming Correspondence, Outgoing Correspondence, General Correspondence, Financial Papers, Business Papers, Subject File, and Miscellany.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms009329.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T14:00:33</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu011001.2</id>
    <title>Boris Koutzen Collection </title>
    <updated>2012-03-28T12:56:41</updated>
    <summary>The Boris Koutzen Collection contains printed and photocopied manuscript music scores, negative photostats and microfilm of holograph music, correspondence, clippings, writings, books, pamphlets, periodicals, programs, photographs, articles, manuscript and typewritten journals, printed biographical sketches, bound and unbound scrapbooks, and a printed catalog of Koutzen's compositions. It also includes a modest acquisition of correspondence and music belonging to his daughter, Nadia Koutzen. The collection spans the years from 1889 to 2005, with the bulk of the materials dating from 1954 to 1965.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu011001.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-01-28T18:14:50</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms010276.2</id>
    <title>American Society of Landscape Architects Records</title>
    <updated>2012-03-28T12:56:41</updated>
    <summary>The records of the American Society of Landscape Architects span the years 1899-1966, with the bulk of the material dating from 1925 to 1955. The collection includes general correspondence, subject files, letterheads of society members, reports from chapters and committees, books, and letterbooks of outgoing correspondence. The records are organized into the following series: General Correspondence, Subject File, Chapter and Committee Reports, Letterheads of Members, Books, and Letterbooks.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms010276.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-03-25T13:31:06</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu012002.2</id>
    <title>Lukas Foss Papers </title>
    <updated>2012-03-28T12:56:41</updated>
    <summary>The Lukas Foss Papers span the period 1926 to 2000, with the majority of the materials dating from 1936 to 1995. The collection consists of holograph manuscript scores and parts, sketches, correspondence, business papers, programs, clippings, promotional materials, contracts, and financial documents.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu012002.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2012-03-28T12:56:41</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu010027.2</id>
    <title>Otto Klemperer Archive </title>
    <updated>2012-03-28T12:56:41</updated>
    <summary>Otto Klemperer is known primarily for his artistry as a conductor, particularly of contemporary music and operas during the 1920s and 1930s, and of orchestral music by Beethoven, Bruckner, Mozart, and Mahler. He is less well-known for his compositions, which include symphonies, string quartets, songs, piano solos, choral works, an opera, and arrangements.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu010027.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-12-20T20:06:53</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms010279.2</id>
    <title>Association of Research Libraries Records</title>
    <updated>2012-03-28T12:56:41</updated>
    <summary>The records of the Association of Research Libraries span the years 1932-1979 and document the efforts of the association to improve the collections and services of member research libraries in North America. The collection consists of correspondence, memoranda, minutes of meetings, reports, financial records, printed matter, and miscellaneous items concerning the organizational structure and administration of the association. The records reflect on membership requirements and admittances, the deliberations of internal and cooperative committees, relationships with affiliated organizations, and various projects administered by the association, including the Farmington Plan, the Public law 480 program, the Foreign Newspaper Microfilm Project, and the publication of the first Library of Congress catalog initiated and sponsored by the association.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms010279.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-07-14T16:55:16</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms011066.2</id>
    <title>Associated Press, Washington, D.C., Bureau, News Dispatches</title>
    <updated>2012-03-28T12:56:41</updated>
    <summary>The collection of news dispatches of the Washington, D.C., Bureau of the Associated Press spans the period 1915-1930 and contain an unbroken chronology of world and national events as reported by the news agency.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms011066.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-07-14T16:55:15</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms010047.2</id>
    <title>Robert Anderson Papers</title>
    <updated>2012-03-28T12:56:41</updated>
    <summary>The papers of Robert Anderson (1805-1871) span the years 1819-1948, with the bulk of the items concentrated in the period 1836-1870. Included in the collection are correspondence and letterbooks, printed matter, drafts of writings, and official documents. Part of the material relates to Anderson's military duty in the Black Hawk War and Mexican War and to his writings on coast defense, ordnance, and artillery tactics. Chief interest centers in his prominent role at the outbreak of the Civil War, when he was commander of the Union garrison during the bombardment of Fort Sumter. Also in the collection are the papers of Anderson's daughter, Eba Anderson Lawton, historian and biographer of her father.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms010047.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-01-28T18:15:02</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms011057.2</id>
    <title>Edward Goodrich Acheson Papers</title>
    <updated>2012-03-28T12:56:41</updated>
    <summary>The papers of Edward Goodrich Acheson (1856-1931) cover the period 1872-1968 with the bulk of the material falling between 1899 and 1930. They consist of diaries, letterbooks, laboratory notebooks, business and general correspondence, and miscellaneous material relating to Acheson's scientific career and his companies. The collection is arranged in Diaries, Letterbooks, Business Correspondence, General Correspondence, Miscellany, and Oversize series. </summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms011057.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-06-21T11:34:57</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms011005.2</id>
    <title>Louise Bates Ames Papers</title>
    <updated>2012-03-28T12:56:41</updated>
    <summary>The papers of Louise Bates Ames (1908-1996) span the period 1915-1989, with the bulk of the material dating from 1950 to 1975. The collection consists primarily of correspondence and manuscript material relating to Ames's career as a child psychologist, cofounder and codirector of the Gesell Institute of Child Development, and author of numerous books and articles on child behavior and child development. Included in the collection are family correspondence, correspondence with friends and professional associates, a sampling of letters related to the syndicated newspaper column Parents Ask, and manuscripts and related correspondence for several of Ames's books and articles. The collection is organized in six original series and five additions. The original series include Family Correspondence, Special Correspondence, General Correspondence, &#x201C;Parents Ask&#x201D; Newspaper Column, Writings, and Miscellany. The additions are dated according to the year of their arrangement and contain material organized in the same schema as the original part.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms011005.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-04-26T15:02:46</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/eadafc.af999001.2</id>
    <title>Juan B. Rael Collection</title>
    <updated>2012-03-28T12:56:41</updated>
    <summary>Juan B. Rael Collection comprises multi-format ethnographic field documentation of religious and secular music of Spanish-speaking residents of rural Northern New Mexico and Southern Colorado. It contains correspondence, administrative materials, recording logs, song transcriptions and translations, and materials generated in the process of creating the online presentation.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadafc.af999001.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:52</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/eadafc.af006002.2</id>
    <title>American Dialect Society Collection</title>
    <updated>2012-03-28T12:56:41</updated>
    <summary>The recordings in the American Dialect Society Collection consist of 893 audio discs (both originals and duplicates made from originals, which replaced absent originals). 466 duplicate discs were subsequently delivered to the Linguistic Archives at the University of Georgia, Athens; AFC retained the original discs from which these were recordings were made. The 891 discs kept by AFC include aluminum-based acetate discs, plastic discs, and 12 shellac pressings made from the original recordings. In some cases the original disc no longer exists and so the copy is the only source for the recording. In addition there is one tape copy of eighteen discs duplicated in 1972 by Frederic Cassidy at the University of Wisconsin.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadafc.af006002.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:50</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms009316.2</id>
    <title>Ethel Armes Collection of Lee Family Papers</title>
    <updated>2012-03-28T12:56:41</updated>
    <summary>The Ethel Armes Collection of Lee Family Papers consists principally of photocopies and transcripts of documents found in other repositories. Armes collected and assembled these in preparation for her book, Stratford Hall: The Great House of the Lees (1936). Materials date from 1671 to 1936 and include family correspondence of the Lee and Shippen families pertaining mainly to life during the Revolutionary War period. The bulk of the correspondence is that of Henry "Lighthorse Harry" Lee, Revolutionary War general and father of Robert E. Lee, and Major Henry Lee, brother of Robert E. Lee. Subjects detailed in the correspondence include military activities during the Revolutionary War, politics and political appointments, financial affairs in the colonies, agriculture, planting, and slavery in Virginia, and family life on Shirley Plantation. Among other family members represented in the collection are Charles Carter Lee, Richard Bland Lee, Mary Randolph Custis and Robert E. Lee, Alice Lee Shippen, Thomas Lee Shippen, and William Shippen. One noteworthy item in the collection is a copy of a letter of former slave Eleanor Berry to Elizabeth Collins Lee, her previous mistress. Duff Green, Nathanael Greene, Alexander Hamilton, James Madison, John Tyler, and George Washington are among the more prominent correspondents in the collection.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms009316.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T14:03:01</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms010274.2</id>
    <title>American Gold Star Mothers, Inc., Records</title>
    <updated>2012-03-28T12:56:41</updated>
    <summary>The records of American Gold Star Mothers, Inc., a national patriotic organization of mothers of American military personnel who lost their lives in the service of the country, span the years 1917-1941. The collection consists of correspondence, membership applications, minute book, clippings, scrapbooks, legal papers, roll and record books, printed and near-print matter, photographs, drafts of legislation, and a copy of the constitution with an appended list of charter members. Also in the collection are press releases and publicity material about conventions, records concerning litigation undertaken to protect the name of the group from infringement, and some papers relating to the insignia of the organization. The scrapbooks contain clippings, invitations, photographs, and programs.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms010274.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-12-20T20:07:02</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms010272.2</id>
    <title>Cleveland Abbe Papers</title>
    <updated>2012-03-28T12:56:41</updated>
    <summary>The papers of the American meteorologist Cleveland Abbe (1838-1916) span the years 1850-1954, with the bulk of the material dated up to 1916. The papers consist mainly of correspondence received by Abbe and a few copies of his replies and are organized into the following series: Diaries, General Correspondence, Family Correspondence and Related Papers, Subject File, Speech and Article File, and Printed Matter. </summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms010272.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-12-20T20:06:59</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/eadafc.af011015.2</id>
    <title>1988 Neptune Plaza Concert Series Collection</title>
    <updated>2012-03-28T12:56:41</updated>
    <summary>The 1988 Neptune Plaza Concert Series Collection consists of manuscript and print materials, audio recordings, and graphic materials that document the 1988 concert series sponsored by the American Folklife Center. The annual series, which began in 1977, features the presentation of folk traditions from many cultures. The concerts take place on the Neptune Plaza at the front of the Jefferson Building of the Library of Congress between April and September. Adverse weather conditions sometimes force the concerts indoors. The 1988 series was produced with the assistance of the National Council for the Traditional Arts.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadafc.af011015.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-09-22T16:17:31</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms010123.2</id>
    <title>American Colony in Jerusalem Collection</title>
    <updated>2012-03-28T12:56:41</updated>
    <summary>The papers in the American Colony in Jerusalem Collection span the years circa 1786-2007, with the bulk of the material dating from 1870 to 1968. The collection documents the history of the American Colony in Jerusalem and its members, particularly the Spafford, Vester, and Whiting families. It covers the events that led to the founding of this cooperative Christian community in the Holy Land, the lives and philanthropic work of American Colony members, the secularization and shift toward incorporation of the religious commune, and the conflict and split between American and Swedish members. It is also a record of life in Jerusalem and Palestine as part of the Ottoman Empire, the British mandate, Jordan, and Israel. Most of the items were collected and saved by Bertha Spafford Vester, who was the daughter of American Colony founders, Horatio Gates Spafford (1828-1888) and Anna T. Spafford, and the community's primary leader following the death of her mother. Other members who fulfilled administrative roles include adopted son Jacob Spafford and son-in-law John D. Whiting. Although most of the items in the collection are written in English, there is also material in Turkish, Arabic, Hebrew, and Swedish. The collection consists of three parts.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms010123.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:40</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms011084.2</id>
    <title>American Rocket Company Records</title>
    <updated>2012-03-28T12:56:41</updated>
    <summary>The records of the American Rocket Company span the years 1958-1991, with the bulk of the material dating from 1981 to 1984. The records are in English and are organized into the following sections: Space Enterprise Consultants, ARC Technologies, Starstruck Corporation, American Rocket Company, legislation, policy development, and miscellany. </summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms011084.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-06-21T11:34:56</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms009314.2</id>
    <title>Henry T. Allen Papers</title>
    <updated>2012-03-28T12:56:41</updated>
    <summary>The papers of Henry Tureman Allen (1859-1930) span the years 1806-1933, with the bulk of the material dating from 1883 to 1933. The collection relates mainly to Allen's military career as a member of an Alaskan exploring party, 1885-1886; as organizer and chief of the Philippine Constabulary, 1901-1907; as a member of the Mexican Punitive Expedition, 1916-1917; as commander of the Ninetieth Division during the First World War, and as commander of the American Occupation Forces on the Rhine, 1919-1923. Subsequent to his retirement from the army in 1923, he was active in organizing various veterans' groups for the 1928 Democratic presidential candidate, Alfred Emanuel Smith; material relating to this political activity is among the papers. A few Allen family papers are also in the collection. The papers are organized into the following series: Diaries, General Correspondence, Letterbooks, Military Matters, Speech, Article, and Book File, Miscellany, Photographs, Printed Matter, Clippings, Maps, Reports, Photograph Albums, Scrapbooks and Portfolio, and Oversize. </summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms009314.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T14:00:33</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms010271.2</id>
    <title>Elisha Hunt Allen Papers</title>
    <updated>2012-03-28T12:56:41</updated>
    <summary>The papers of Elisha Hunt Allen (1804-1883) span the years 1849-1934, with the bulk of the material dating from 1867 to 1882. The papers consist of correspondence, speeches and writings, notes, awards and diplomas, invitations, passports, photographs, statistical tables, printed matter, and miscellaneous items and are organized into the following series: Family Correspondence, General Correspondence, Hawaiian Legation Correspondence, Subject File, Miscellany, and Oversize.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms010271.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-12-20T20:06:59</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu012003.2</id>
    <title>George Crumb Papers</title>
    <updated>2012-03-28T12:56:41</updated>
    <summary>The George Crumb Papers span the period 1956 to 2011, with the majority of the materials dating from 1965 to 2003. The collection consists of holograph manuscript scores and sketches, correspondence and business papers, and a series of meticulously assembled scrapbooks chronicling Crumb's distinguished career as a composer. </summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu012003.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2012-03-28T12:56:41</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms010046.2</id>
    <title>William A. H. Allen Papers</title>
    <updated>2012-03-28T12:56:41</updated>
    <summary>The papers of William A. H. Allen (fl. 1863-1890) span the years 1863-1884. The collection consists of journals with photographs, sketches, and illustrations describing Allen's activities while serving on the Cayuga (ship), 1863-1864, assigned to blockade duty on the Gulf Coast during the Civil War, and subsequently on ships in the Mediterranean, Indian, and Pacific Oceans, and at stations on the east and west coasts of the United States and Europe, including on an around-the-world tour in 1881-1884 on the sloop-of-war Lancaster. </summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms010046.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-12-20T20:07:00</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/eadafc.af011006.2</id>
    <title> 1979 Neptune Plaza Concert Series Collection</title>
    <updated>2012-03-28T12:56:41</updated>
    <summary>The 1979 Neptune Plaza Concert Series Collection consists of manuscript and print materials, audio recordings, and graphic materials that document the 1979 concert series sponsored by the American Folklife Center. The annual series, which began in 1977, features the presentation of folk traditions from many cultures. The concerts take place on the Neptune Plaza at the front of the Jefferson Building of the Library of Congress between April and September. The 1979 series was produced with the assistance of the National Council for the Traditional Arts.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadafc.af011006.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-05-23T14:32:12</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms011065.2</id>
    <title>Henry Justin Allen Papers</title>
    <updated>2012-03-28T12:56:41</updated>
    <summary>The papers of Henry Justin Allen (1868-1950) span the years 1896-1942, with the bulk concentrated in the period 1919-1942. The collection is organized in three series: Pre-Gubernatorial File, Gubernatorial File, and Post-Gubernatorial File. Letters concerning family affairs, including occasional letters to his wife, are scattered throughout the collection. Material relating to his business activities is located in both the Gubernatorial and Post-Gubernatorial Files. </summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms011065.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-07-14T16:55:02</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu010005.2</id>
    <title>Dorothea Dix Lawrence Collection </title>
    <updated>2012-03-28T12:56:41</updated>
    <summary>The Dorothea Dix Lawrence Collection consists of the correspondence, photographs, clippings, and writings of this noted operatic singer, recitalist, lecturer, and folklorist. The collection also includes piano-vocal opera scores and a large number of American folk songs. </summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu010005.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:02</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms010049.2</id>
    <title>Samuel Edward Axson Sermons</title>
    <updated>2012-03-28T12:56:41</updated>
    <summary>The sermons of Samuel Edward Axson (circa 1836-1884) span the years 1857-1880 and consist mainly of holograph sermons and devotional talks by Axson written in various hands. Most were delivered during his pastorate at the First Presbyterian Church in Rome, Georgia, 1866-1884, but they include presentations at Augusta, George, where he was city missionary in the 1850s, and at Presbyterian churches in Beech Island, McPherson, and Madison, South Carolina, as well as at Savannah, Georgia, and New Orleans, Louisiana, together with talks before Methodist and Baptist congregants.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms010049.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-12-20T20:07:09</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms009118.2</id>
    <title>Maude Adams Papers</title>
    <updated>2012-03-28T12:56:41</updated>
    <summary>The papers of Maude Adams (1872-1953) span the years circa 1925-circa 1956. The entire collection is composed of writings by Maude Adams and a draft by Phyllis Robbins of her biography of Adams, Maude Adams: An Intimate Portrait, published in 1956. The writings of Adams include both published and typescript versions of magazine articles, a speech, a religious play, a book-length typescript and a pamphlet for teaching speech, and a proposal with scripts for a radio program with Homer Saint-Gaudens.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms009118.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T14:01:27</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms011190.2</id>
    <title>Arthur Family Papers</title>
    <updated>2012-03-28T12:56:41</updated>
    <summary>The papers of the Arthur family span the years 1817 to 1972, with the bulk of the items concentrated in the period 1874-1972. Although the collection consists largely of the papers of Chester Alan Arthur II (1864-1937) and Chester Alan Arthur III (1901-1972), it includes papers of President Chester Alan Arthur's sister, Malvina Ann Arthur Haynesworth; his brother, William A. Arthur, Jr.; Chester Alan Arthur II's first wife, Myra Fithian Andrews; his sister, Ellen Arthur Pinkerton; Chester Alan Arthur III's first wife, Charlotte Wilson Arthur, and his second wife, Esther Murphy Strachey Arthur. Other members of the Arthur Andrews, and Fifthian families are also represented in the collection. The papers are organized in ten series: Chester Alan Arthur II Papers, Myra Fithian Andrews Arthur Papers, Ellen Arthur Pinkerton Papers, Chester Alan Arthur III Papers, Malvina Ann Arthur Haynesworth Papers, William A. Arthur, Jr., Papers, Andrews Family Papers, Fithian Family Papers, Miscellany, and Oversize.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms011190.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2012-01-19T20:07:10</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu010024.2</id>
    <title>Adolph Bolm Collection</title>
    <updated>2012-03-28T12:56:41</updated>
    <summary>The collection consists of materials that document Adolph Bolm's career as a dancer and choreographer in both Russia and the United States throughout the first half of the twentieth century. The Photographs series includes production photographs from the various companies with which Bolm worked, including the Ballets Russes de Serge Diaghilev, Ballet Intime, Adolph Bolm Ballet, Chicago Civic Opera, San Francisco Opera, and the Ballet Theatre (later called the American Ballet Theatre). The Programs series documents Bolm&#x2019;s work with touring and resident companies, including the aforementioned companies. The Advertisements and Pamphlets series contains marketing materials for Ballet Theatre&#x2019;s California tour and advertisements for Bolm&#x2019;s Hollywood and Chicago dance studios. The Articles series includes biographical articles, performance reviews and other press clippings. The Correspondence series contains considerable correspondence between Bolm and composer John Alden Carpenter, a frequent collaborator and family friend. The Business Papers include contracts, financial agreements, travel documents, and an address book. The Anna Pavlova Materials series includes telegrams, letters, and an homage written by Bolm about Pavlova, one of his favorite ballerinas. The Writings series provides detailed biographical information about the early parts of Bolm&#x2019;s life in St. Petersburg, as well as some press materials summarizing his career in the United States. It also includes Rosalind Shaffer De Mille&#x2019;s notes and drafts from interviews with Bolm and others for a biography of Bolm. The Artwork series contains costume designs and paintings. The Commemorative Items and Music Scores series includes two Igor Stravinsky published scores, one with an inscription, and autograph books containing signatures from many composers and artists.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu010024.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-10-29T17:55:39</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/eadafc.af011020.2</id>
    <title>1993 Neptune Plaza Concert Series Collection</title>
    <updated>2012-03-28T12:56:41</updated>
    <summary>The 1993 Neptune Plaza Concert Series Collection consists of manuscript and print materials, sound recordings, graphic materials, and moving images that document the 1993 concert series sponsored by the American Folklife Center. The annual series, which began in 1977, features the presentation of folk traditions from many cultures. The concerts take place on the Neptune Plaza at the front of the Jefferson Building of the Library of Congress between April and September. Adverse weather conditions sometimes force the concerts indoors.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadafc.af011020.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2012-02-16T13:15:26</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu003006.2</id>
    <title>Ernst Bacon Collection</title>
    <updated>2012-03-28T12:56:41</updated>
    <summary>Materials in the Ernst Bacon Collection span his entire ninety-one year life. They include five series: Music, Writings, Correspondence, Iconography, and Miscellaneous materials. The bulk of materials are found in the Music, Correspondence, and Writings series.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu003006.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:32</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms011110.2</id>
    <title>Chandler P. Anderson Papers</title>
    <updated>2012-03-28T12:56:41</updated>
    <summary>The papers of Chandler Parsons Anderson (1866-1936) cover the period 1894-1953, with the bulk of the material from 1896 to 1929. The collection is organized into Diary, General Correspondence, Office File, Subject File, Speeches and Writings, Miscellany, and Oversize series.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms011110.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-10-25T14:51:46</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms010280.2</id>
    <title>Amory Austin Collection Relating to Heraldry</title>
    <updated>2012-03-28T12:56:41</updated>
    <summary>The Amory Austin Collection Relating to Heraldry spans the years circa 1865-1917 and consists of notes, notebooks, and other papers relating to heraldry collected by Austin. Included also is an obituary of Ivers James Austin, a Massachusetts politician, and a letter to him.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms010280.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-12-20T20:07:10</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms009312.2</id>
    <title>Leason Heberling Adams Papers</title>
    <updated>2012-03-28T12:56:41</updated>
    <summary>The papers of Leason Heberling Adams (1887-1969) span the years 1919-1968. The collection consists of personal and professional correspondence, notebooks, notes, published writings on scientific research, and miscellaneous printed matter that are organized into the following series: Correspondence, Writings, and Miscellany.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms009312.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T14:02:35</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/eadafc.af011008.2</id>
    <title> 1981 Neptune Plaza Concert Series Collection</title>
    <updated>2012-03-28T12:56:41</updated>
    <summary>The 1981 Neptune Plaza Concert Series Collection consists of manuscript and print materials, audio recordings, and graphic materials that document the 1981 concert series sponsored by the American Folklife Center. The annual series, which began in 1977, features the presentation of folk traditions from many cultures. The concerts take place on the Neptune Plaza at the front of the Jefferson Building of the Library of Congress between May and October. Adverse weather conditions sometimes force the concerts indoors. The 1981 series was produced with the assistance of the National Council for the Traditional Arts.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadafc.af011008.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-05-23T14:32:20</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms009313.2</id>
    <title>Florence Ellinwood Allen Papers</title>
    <updated>2012-03-28T12:56:41</updated>
    <summary>The papers of Florence Ellinwood Allen (1884-1966) span the period 1907-1965 and relate to her position as associate justice of the Ohio Supreme Court and as judge on the United States Court of Appeals for the Sixth Circuit. Allen was an active feminist instrumental in obtaining women's suffrage and the first woman to sit on an American court of last resort. She was also the first woman in the United States to occupy the position of senior judge of a federal court of appeals. The papers are organized into the following series: Correspondence, Subject File, Speech and Article File, and Miscellany.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms009313.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:53</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms009107.2</id>
    <title>Association Against the Prohibition Amendment Records</title>
    <updated>2012-03-28T12:56:41</updated>
    <summary>The records of the Association against the Prohibition Amendment span the years 1917-1933. The bulk of the collection consists of anti-prohibition articles clipped from newspapers and magazines. Also included is the association's certificate of foundation, two annual reports, pamphlets printed by the society, bibliographies of anti-prohibition literature, and a mailing list.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms009107.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T14:00:34</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms009272.2</id>
    <title>Karl Abraham Papers</title>
    <updated>2012-03-28T12:56:41</updated>
    <summary>The papers of Karl Abraham (1877-1925) span the years 1908-1925 and document Abraham&#x2019;s role in the founding of psychoanalysis, particularly in his native Germany. The papers consist largely of letters from psychoanalysts and others associated with the movement, including Lou Andreas-Salom&#xE9;, Eugen Bleuler, Franz Deuticke, Wilhelm Fliess, G. Stanley Hall, Ernest Jones, C. G. Jung, Otto Rank, and Theodor Reik. Two letters from Abraham to Max Eitingon written in 1908 are included as well. Also featured in the collection are circular letters from the International Psycho-Analytical Association during Abraham&#x2019;s presidency from 1924 to 1925 and statements concerning psychoanalytic training drafted during the 1920s. An addition to the papers in 2001 consists of two letters written by Abraham, a letter from Hanns Sachs to Abraham, and a letter from Nelly Wolffheim to Abraham&#x2019;s widow, Hedwig Abraham. Miscellaneous items include a photocopy of a book inscription by Sigmund Freud and a photocopy of a program from the opening of Abraham&#x2019;s psychoanalytic outpatient clinic in Berlin in 1920.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms009272.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T14:01:53</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/eadafc.af005001.2</id>
    <title>Anne and Frank Warner Collection </title>
    <updated>2012-03-28T12:56:41</updated>
    <summary>The collection contains sound recordings and photographs made by Anne and Frank Warner that document musicians and storytellers from numerous traditions. The materials were collected during field trips to Illinois (1941), Massachusetts (1941), Missouri (1941), New Hampshire (1940-1941), New York (1939-1941, 1946, 1949-1952, 1961, 1969), North Carolina (1938-1941, 1944, 1951, 1959),Vermont (1940), and Virginia (1940).</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadafc.af005001.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:51</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms010275.2</id>
    <title>American Medical Center for Burma Records</title>
    <updated>2012-03-28T12:56:41</updated>
    <summary>The records of the American Medical Center for Burma span the years 1945-1966, with the bulk of the material falling between 1959-1965. The American Medical Center for Burma, with a main office in New York, was a nonsectarian, nonprofit organization founded in 1946 to support the Namkham Hospital and Midwives and Nurses Training School founded by Gordon Stifler Seagrave, the famed "Burma Surgeon," in Namkhan, Burma, in 1922. The American Medical Center for Burma was reorganized in 1959 to give even greater financial support to Seagrave and the Namkham Hospital. The records of the American Medical Center for Burma consist primarily of correspondence between Seagrave and the staff, officers, and Board of Directors of the organization and are organized into the following series: General Correspondence, Special Correspondence, Financial Contributors' Correspondence, Newspaper Clippings, Printed Matter, Miscellany, Addition, and Oversize. The main body of correspondence is supported by administrative files of the organization, newspaper clippings, printed matter, financial records, and a galley proof of one of Seagrave's books, Life of a Burma Surgeon, published in 1960 by Ballantine Books.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms010275.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-03-25T13:30:54</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms011070.2</id>
    <title>American Federation of Labor Records</title>
    <updated>2012-03-28T12:56:41</updated>
    <summary>The records of the American Federation of Labor (AFL) consist of letterpress books of the correspondence of Samuel Gompers and William Green, presidents of the organization, and by other officials including James Duncan, Gabriel Edmonston, Frank Keyes Foster, and John McBride. The collection is arranged, filed, and numbered as received. Volumes 251, 310, and 313 were not received by the Library. Each volume contains an index of correspondents. </summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms011070.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-08-19T16:21:26</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu012001.2</id>
    <title>Vivian Fine Music Manuscripts </title>
    <updated>2012-02-16T13:15:26</updated>
    <summary>The Vivian Fine Music Manuscripts chiefly consist of holograph scores, sketches, and parts for works written between 1929 and 1993. Fine's compositions spanned a variety of musical genres: solo instrumental, chamber, orchestral, as well as accompanied vocal and choral pieces. Notable compositions include Capriccio for Oboe and String Trio (1946), The Great Wall of China (1946), Fine's collaboration with Martha Graham, Alcestis (1960), and chamber operas The Women in the Garden (1978) and Memoirs of Uliana Rooney (1994). A small quantity of correspondence, programs, and clippings supplement the music manuscripts. The correspondence captures Fine's years of compositional growth while studying with Ruth Crawford (Seeger) and making acquaintances with figures such as Henry Cowell, George Antheil, Dane Rudhyar, and Aaron Copland.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu012001.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2012-02-16T13:15:26</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/eadafc.af010003.2</id>
    <title> 1977 Neptune Plaza Concert Series Collection</title>
    <updated>2012-02-16T13:15:26</updated>
    <summary>The 1977 Neptune Plaza Concert Series Collection consists of manuscript and print materials, audio recordings, and graphic materials that document the 1977 concert series sponsored by the American Folklife Center. The annual series, which began in 1977, features the presentation of folk traditions from many cultures. The concerts took place on the Neptune Plaza at the front of the Jefferson Building of the Library of Congress between April and October. Adverse weather conditions sometimes forced the concerts indoors. The 1977 series was produced with the assistance of the National Council for the Traditional Arts.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadafc.af010003.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-03-04T15:34:43</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms008049.2</id>
    <title>Bernard L. Austin Papers</title>
    <updated>2012-02-16T13:15:26</updated>
    <summary>The papers of Bernard Lige Austin (1902-1979), a naval officer who achieved distinction as a commander of submarines and destroyers and as an administrator, educator, military diplomat, and press officer, span the years 1916-1979, with the bulk of the material concentrated in the period 1937-1968. The collection is organized into series of Correspondence, Speeches and Writings, Subject File, Classified, Top Secret, and North American Treaty Organization. Austin attended The Citadel at Charleston in his native South Carolina before matriculating at the United States Naval Academy, from which he was graduated in 1924. His first independent command was as captain of the submarine R-11 during 1934-1937. In the late 1930s, while serving as a press officer for the Navy Department, Austin wrote articles on submarine warfare for the Encyclopedia Britannica and the World Book Encyclopedia. His submarine expertise was again called on late in his career when he presided over courts of inquiry investigating the loss of the nuclear powered submarines Thresher (1963) and Scorpion (1968).</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms008049.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T14:03:25</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/eadafc.af000001.2</id>
    <title>Vance Randolph Collection</title>
    <updated>2012-02-16T13:15:26</updated>
    <summary>The Vance Randolph Collection had its beginnings in the early 1940s with fieldwork conducted by the well-known "amateur" Ozark folklorist Vance Randolph. In February 1941, Alan Lomax, then head of the Archive of American Folk Song at the Library of Congress, wrote to Vance Randolph, asking if he would consider making field recordings in the Ozarks. Randolph accepted the request and began to conduct fieldwork with recording equipment and film supplied by the Archive. By the end of 1942, he had collected more than 870 selections on 198 discs (either aluminum or glass-based and lacquer) for the Library of Congress and photographs of people he recorded. Randolph used much of the material he collected in his book Ozark Folksongs, while the Archive included selections from these field recordings on the following releases: L-12, Anglo-American Songs and Ballads; L-14, Anglo-American Songs and Ballads; L-20, Anglo-American Songs and Ballads; L-30, Songs of the Mormons and Songs of the West (this release includes Randolph himself singing "Starving to Death on a Government Claim"); L-61, Railroad Songs and Ballads; and L-62, American Fiddle Tunes. </summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadafc.af000001.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:45</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms009008.2</id>
    <title>Maxwell Anderson Papers</title>
    <updated>2012-02-16T13:15:26</updated>
    <summary>The papers of Maxwell Anderson (1888-1959) span the years 1920-1989, with the bulk of the items concentrated in the period 1920-1955. The collection consists of letters to and from Harold Monro and copies of various plays and screenplays by Anderson, including scripts which he submitted for copyright to the Library of Congress Copyright Office. Among the drafts, corrected galleys, and annotated copies are scripts for &#x201C;Anne of the Thousand Days,&#x201D; &#x201C;Joan of Lorraine,&#x201D; &#x201C;The Eve of St. Mark,&#x201D; and &#x201C;What Price Glory.&#x201D;</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms009008.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T14:01:54</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms998013.2</id>
    <title>Alex. Brown&amp;Sons Records</title>
    <updated>2012-02-16T13:15:26</updated>
    <summary>The records of Alex. Brown&amp;Sons span the years 1796-1908, with the bulk of the material dating from 1796 to 1884. Included are business records of successor companies, subsidiaries, and allied business. The records document the commercial and financial activities of Alexander Brown, his sons, and their successors, showing the development of their banking house in conjunction with extensive import-export operations, the building of ships and worldwide trade activities, and the building of the Baltimore&amp;Ohio Railroad. They also reflect the company's change from a mercantile to an international banking house having connections with Brown, Shipley&amp;Company of Liverpool, and with Brown Brothers&amp;Company, of New York, Philadelphia, and Baltimore. The records are organized into the following series: Lettercopy Books, Letterpress Books, Daybooks, Cashbooks, Ledgers, Sterling Ledgers, Ledger Sight Bills, Journals, Sales Books, Waste Books, Accounts Current, Blotters, and Miscellany. </summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms998013.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T14:02:03</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms008095.2</id>
    <title>Joseph Alsop and Stewart Alsop Papers</title>
    <updated>2012-02-16T13:15:26</updated>
    <summary>The papers of Joseph Wright Alsop (1910-1989) and Stewart Johonnot Oliver Alsop (1914-1974) span the years 1699-1989, with the bulk of the material concentrated in the period 1937-1989. The collection includes correspondence, family papers, office files, speeches and writings, travel files, financial matter, subject files, miscellaneous items, and classified material. The Alsop Papers have been organized into four parts. </summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms008095.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T14:00:25</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms001007.2</id>
    <title>Allen Varley Astin Papers</title>
    <updated>2012-02-16T13:15:26</updated>
    <summary>The papers of Allen Varley Astin (1904-1984) span the years 1921-1984 with the bulk of the material concentrated in the period 1950-1970. The collection is organized into three series. The National Bureau of Standards series documents Astin's forty-year career at the bureau, most especially his role as director, 1952-1969. The Professional Activities series documents his association with scientific, academic, governmental, and public administration organizations. A small file concerning his term as acting assistant secretary for science and technology at the Commerce Department is combined with a few family and personal papers into a Miscellany series.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms001007.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T14:03:34</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms001006.2</id>
    <title>William Allen Papers</title>
    <updated>2012-02-16T13:15:26</updated>
    <summary>The papers of William Allen (1803-1879) span the years 1796-1879, with the bulk of the items concentrated in the period 1840-1876. The collection focuses on his career in Ohio politics, first as United States representative and senator, then as governor of Ohio. Included are correspondence, speeches, memoranda, financial records, printed matter, maps, and other material. The papers are arranged in a bound Chronological File and a Miscellany. </summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms001006.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T14:00:10</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/eadafc.af011021.2</id>
    <title>1994 Neptune Plaza Concert Series Collection</title>
    <updated>2012-02-16T13:15:26</updated>
    <summary>The 1994 Neptune Plaza Concert Series Collection consists of manuscript and print materials, sound recordings, graphic materials, and moving images that document the 1994 concert series sponsored by the American Folklife Center. The annual series, which began in 1977, features the presentation of folk traditions from many cultures. The concerts take place on the Neptune Plaza at the front of the Jefferson Building of the Library of Congress between April and September. Adverse weather conditions sometimes force the concerts indoors.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadafc.af011021.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2012-02-16T13:15:26</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms006048.2</id>
    <title>Gloria Hollister Anable Papers</title>
    <updated>2012-02-16T13:15:26</updated>
    <summary> The papers of Gloria Elaine Hollister Anable (1900-1988) span the years 1916-2003, with most of the material concentrated in the period 1929-1936. Journals, correspondence, writings, clippings, notes, and photographs comprise the bulk of the collection. It is arranged alphabetically by type of material or name of topic and thereunder chronologically. </summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms006048.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:41</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms009105.2</id>
    <title>American Society of Adlerian Psychology Records</title>
    <updated>2012-02-16T13:15:26</updated>
    <summary>The records of the American Society of Adlerian Psychology span the years 1951-1970 and consist of correspondence, minute books, membership lists, and organizational material relating to the history and incorporation of an organization founded in 1951 to foster the work and teachings of Adlerian psychology and its founder, Alfred Adler.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms009105.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T14:02:53</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms007097.2</id>
    <title>Hendrik Christian Andersen Papers</title>
    <updated>2012-02-16T13:15:26</updated>
    <summary>The papers of Hendrik Christian Andersen (1872-1940) span the years 1844-1940, with the bulk of the material concentrated in the period 1890-1920. The papers reflect Andersen's interest in the arts and in the creation of a world capital. The collection is organized into the following series: Diaries, Family Papers, General Correspondence, Notebooks, Writings, Olivia Cushing Andersen Papers, Miscellany, and Oversize.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms007097.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T14:01:28</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms009099.2</id>
    <title>Samuel Adams Papers</title>
    <updated>2012-02-16T13:15:26</updated>
    <summary> The papers of Samuel Adams (1722-1803) span the years 1635-1826 and consist of reproductions of originals in the New York Public Library documenting Adams&#x2019;s political career in Massachusetts and some family matters. Included is correspondence, speeches, petitions, committee records, public documents relating to Massachusetts, and pseudonymous articles submitted to Boston newspapers and attributed to Samuel Adams. A considerable amount of material does not pertain directly to Adams, either as writer or recipient.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms009099.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T14:02:02</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms009074.2</id>
    <title>Luis Aury Papers</title>
    <updated>2012-02-16T13:15:26</updated>
    <summary>The papers of Luis Aury (circa 1787-circa 1821) span the years 1801-1911, with the bulk of the material dating from 1801 to 1822. The papers, written in French and Spanish, include originals and copies of correspondence, records relating to the settlement of Aury's estate, legal documents, a commission, and a newspaper. The correspondence consists largely of letters written by Aury to his family between 1801 and 1816. One of the earliest of these, written while Aury was still an apprentice, describes his experiences as a member of French naval forces sent to Saint-Dominigue in 1802. Letters after 1808 recount his exploits as a corsair conducting raids on English and Spanish ships in the Caribbean.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms009074.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T14:01:25</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms010277.2</id>
    <title>Frank Maloy Anderson Papers</title>
    <updated>2012-02-16T13:15:26</updated>
    <summary>The papers of Frank Maloy Anderson (1871-1961) span the years circa 1895-circa 1961 and consist of correspondence, memorabilia, and an extensive file of research notes for books, studies, articles, and lectures organized within two series: General Correspondence and Related Material and Speech, Article, and Book File. </summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms010277.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-03-25T13:30:57</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms997009.2</id>
    <title>Susan B. Anthony Papers</title>
    <updated>2012-02-16T13:15:26</updated>
    <summary>The papers of Susan Brownell Anthony (1820-1906) span the period from 1846 to 1934, although the bulk of the material dates from 1846 to 1906. The papers include correspondence, a daybook, diaries, scrapbooks, speeches, and miscellaneous items.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms997009.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T14:00:34</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms003055.2</id>
    <title>Philip Hauge Abelson Papers</title>
    <updated>2012-02-16T13:15:26</updated>
    <summary>The papers of Philip Hauge Abelson (1913- ) span the years 1939-2002, with the bulk of the material dating from 1970 to 1989. The papers are organized in the following series: Committees and Organizations, Science Magazine, Speeches and Writings, and a Miscellany consisting of awards, biographical material, general correspondence, photographs, and printed material.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms003055.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:29</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/eadafc.af011007.2</id>
    <title> 1980 Neptune Plaza Concert Series Collection</title>
    <updated>2012-02-16T13:15:26</updated>
    <summary>The 1980 Neptune Plaza Concert Series Collection consists of manuscript and print materials, audio recordings, and graphic materials that document the 1980 concert series sponsored by the American Folklife Center. The annual series, which began in 1977, features the presentation of folk traditions from many cultures. The concerts take place on the Neptune Plaza at the front of the Jefferson Building of the Library of Congress between April and October. The 1980 series was produced with the assistance of the National Council for the Traditional Arts.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadafc.af011007.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-05-23T14:32:19</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.gdc/eadgdc.gc006001.2</id>
    <title>L&#x2019;Aerophile Collection</title>
    <updated>2012-02-16T13:15:26</updated>
    <summary>The fifteen thousand or so items contained in the 152 boxes of the Library of Congress collection include blueprints and manufactures' information of early French and foreign aircraft and dirigibles, reports of accidents involving flyers and balloonists, aerial photographs from World War I, and a series of French cartoons from the period 1909 - 1912 related to aviation. The collection also contains hundreds of photographs of early aviators and designers, including pictures of Charles Lindbergh and his wife Anne Morrow being feted in Paris during their European trip of 1933. A large number of L'Aerophile images appeared in the National Air and Space Museum's major exhibition in 2003 celebrating the centennial of the Wright brothers' first flight, titled the Wright Brothers&amp;the Invention of the Aerial Age.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadgdc.gc006001.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:40</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms008126.2</id>
    <title>American Friends Service Committee Records</title>
    <updated>2012-02-16T13:15:26</updated>
    <summary>The records of the American Friends Service Committee span the years 1933-1988, but are concentrated in the period 1933-1938 and consist of correspondence, an article, a diary/journal, photographs, and related documentation. The most significant item is a typescript diary with appended reports written by Herbert and Jo Abraham from daily records kept by their nine-member team of Home Service section volunteer workers serving a mining community in Letcher County, Kentucky, from June to August 1933. The American Friends Service Committee, organized by the Quakers, promotes peace and reconciliation and the relief of human suffering through its social service and relief programs. In 1933, the organization targeted rural coal mining districts as areas of special concern. The diary details the efforts of these Home Service volunteers to improve social conditions in Hemphill, Kentucky.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms008126.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T14:04:19</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms009043.2</id>
    <title>Adams Family Papers </title>
    <updated>2012-02-16T13:15:26</updated>
    <summary>The Adams Family Papers span the years 1776 to 1948 with the bulk dated 1794-1846. Chiefly comprising correspondence of John Quincy Adams, the collection also includes correspondence and other material relating to Abigail Adams, Charles Francis Adams (1807-1886), Charles Francis Adams (1835-1915), Henry Adams, John Adams, Louisa Catherine Adams, and Samuel Adams. Henry Adams included his address to the American Historical Association in a letter dated 1894 to Herbert Baxter Adams. Many of the items are transcripts, photocopies, and other reproductions. Some of the twentieth century items are explanatory cover letters or printed material. Other correspondents include Joseph Blunt, Alexander Hill Everett, Thomas Jefferson, James Madison, and Robert Welsh, Jr. </summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms009043.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T14:00:03</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms007007.2</id>
    <title>Archivo Nacional de Cuba Collection Pertaining to Spanish Colonial Rule in Louisiana and the Floridas</title>
    <updated>2012-02-16T13:15:26</updated>
    <summary>Transcripts of the records of the Archivo Nacional de Cuba span the years 1770-1911, with the bulk of the material dating from 1770 to 1805. The records are in Spanish and English and concern the Spanish colonial administration of Louisiana and Florida. With the exception of a handwritten &#x201C;Index of correspondence,&#x201D; the items are blueprint copies made sometime before 1913 of typewritten transcripts of documents in the Cuban archive. The transcripts may have resulted from the work of the Carnegie Institution of Washington. Its Department of Historical Research was dedicated to finding documentary sources for the study of American history in foreign archives and publishing a series of guides. The Guide to the Materials for American History in Cuban Archives by Luis Marino Perez was published in 1907. Records in the present collection are described in the Perez book as document numbers 347, 375, and appendix A. A copy of this guide is in the Manuscript Division Reading Room. </summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms007007.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T14:02:03</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms009144.2</id>
    <title>Alfred Adler Papers</title>
    <updated>2012-02-16T13:15:26</updated>
    <summary>The papers of Alfred Adler (1870-1937) span the years 1888-1975, with the bulk of material dating from 1928 to 1937. The papers contain correspondence, lectures, articles, manuscript of a book, an appointment book, patient case studies and record books, reports, notes, photographs, certificates, clippings, and printed matter. The major part of the collection consists of letters written by Adler to his wife and children between 1897 and 1937 and drafts of lectures and articles, many of which Adler wrote while residing in the United States. Correspondence with people outside the Adler family includes a letter written by Albert Einstein in 1937 comparing the theories of Sigmund Freud and Adler. </summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms009144.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T14:03:22</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms007006.2</id>
    <title>Aero Club of America Scrapbooks</title>
    <updated>2012-02-16T13:15:26</updated>
    <summary>The scrapbooks of the Aero Club of America span the years 1891-1912. The club, founded in 1905 to promote the cause of aeronautics, was interested in the potential represented by flying machines. The collection consists of scrapbooks of newspaper clippings, some of which predate the club&#x2019;s founding by sixteen years, chronicling the advent of flight by airplane, airship, and other methods. </summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms007006.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T14:02:46</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms006002.2</id>
    <title>Martin Agronsky Papers</title>
    <updated>2012-02-16T13:15:26</updated>
    <summary>The papers of Martin Agronsky (1915-1999) span the years 1907-1999, with the bulk of the material dating from 1940 to 1990. The papers are organized in the following series: Correspondence, Speeches and Writings File, and a Miscellany consisting primarily of appointment books, awards, biographical material, and items related to organizations with which Agronsky was associated.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms006002.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:30</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms001004.2</id>
    <title>Hannah Arendt Papers</title>
    <updated>2012-02-16T13:15:26</updated>
    <summary>The papers of Hannah Arendt (1906-1975) span the period 1898-1977, with the bulk of the material beginning in 1948, three years prior to her naturalization as an American citizen. The collection is organized in the following series: Family Papers, Correspondence, Adolf Eichmann File, Subject File, Speeches and Writings File, Clippings, Addition I, Addition II, Addition III, and Oversize. Rich in manuscripts and correspondence for Arendt's productive years as a writer and lecturer after World War II, the papers are sparse before the mid-1940s because of Arendt's forced departure from Nazi Germany in 1933 and her escape from occupied France in 1941. Exceptions to the lack of documentation for the first part of her life include a few notebooks and writings, several official and private records relating mainly to her divorce, family history, and emigration, and a small group of personal correspondence with her second husband, Heinrich Bl&#xFC;cher, some of whose letters and unpublished writings can be found in the Family Papers series. Much of the material is in German and other European languages.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms001004.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T14:01:28</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms007107.2</id>
    <title>Thomas Bailey Aldrich Papers</title>
    <updated>2012-02-16T13:15:26</updated>
    <summary> The papers of Thomas Bailey Aldrich (1836-1907) span the years 1873-1901 and consist of correspondence and a bound volume containing both a holograph and typescript of "Monody on the Death of Wendell Phillips." The correspondence contains letters sent by Aldrich and his wife concerning personal and social matters. Most of the correspondence is to Aldrich's friend, Edward Howard House. </summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms007107.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T14:01:26</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms009100.2</id>
    <title>Fred Allen Radio Scripts</title>
    <updated>2012-02-16T13:15:26</updated>
    <summary>The radio scripts of Fred Allen (1894-1956) span the years 1934-1949 and consist of copyright deposits of radio scripts and broadcasts for Town Hall Tonight, The Chesterfield Supper Club, the Jack Benny Show, Bing Crosby Show, Bob Hope Show, and Henry Morgan Show, and Talullah Bankhead's program, The Big Show. The collection is arranged by date of copyright.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms009100.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T14:00:32</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/eadafc.af007001.2</id>
    <title> Sam Eskin Collection, 1939-1969</title>
    <updated>2012-02-16T13:15:26</updated>
    <summary>While Sam Eskin's interests were broad in scope, his multi-format collection of manuscripts, published materials, sound recordings, and still images concentrates and builds upon his early interests in American folk music.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadafc.af007001.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:55</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms009031.2</id>
    <title>Atlantic Union Committee Records</title>
    <updated>2012-02-16T13:15:26</updated>
    <summary>The records of the Atlantic Union Committee span the years 1940-1968, with the bulk of the material from 1949 to 1952. The Atlantic Union Committee was organized in 1949 by Justice Owen J. Roberts as an independent committee of Federal Union, Inc., formed in 1939 by Clarence K. Streit, author of Union Now, published in the same year. The goal of the committee was to persuade the United States Congress to pass a resolution calling for a federal convention, like the one in Philadelphia in 1787, to explore the possibility of union among the Atlantic democracies of North America and Europe. The Atlantic Union Committee was dissolved in 1961 without having achieved its goal. The collection is arranged in four parts as described below.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms009031.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T14:02:02</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms007005.2</id>
    <title>Henry L. Abbot Family Papers</title>
    <updated>2012-02-16T13:15:26</updated>
    <summary>The papers of the family of Henry Larcom Abbot (1831-1927) span the years 1770-2001, with the bulk of the material concentrated in the period 1832-1870. Correspondence, diaries, memoirs, military records, financial and legal records, genealogical material, photographs, writings, clippings, and mementos comprise the major part of the collection. The material is arranged alphabetically by type of material or name of creator and chronologically thereunder. Artifacts and oversize material are arranged and described according to the containers and folders from which the items were removed.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms007005.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:32</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms008024.2</id>
    <title>Frederick Lewis Allen Papers</title>
    <updated>2012-02-16T13:15:26</updated>
    <summary> The papers of Frederick Lewis Allen span the years 1890-1954, with the bulk of the material concentrated in the period 1933-1954. The papers are organized in five series: Diaries, Date Books, and Biographical Material; General Correspondence; Subject File; Literary File; and an Addition.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms008024.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T14:00:33</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms009154.2</id>
    <title>Adee Family Papers</title>
    <updated>2012-02-16T13:15:26</updated>
    <summary>The papers of the Adee family span the years 1824-1966 and consist of awards, catalogs, correspondence, journals, a medical degree, newspaper clippings, poetry, speeches, and writings. The papers are chiefly those of Augustus Alvey Adee (1802-1844), United States Navy surgeon, and his sons David Graham Adee (1837-1901), author and lawyer, and Alvey A. Adee (1842-1924), assistant secretary of state and chief of the Diplomatic Bureau, Department of State.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms009154.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T14:01:27</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms009030.2</id>
    <title>American Psychological Association Records</title>
    <updated>2012-02-16T13:15:26</updated>
    <summary>The records of the American Psychological Association (APA) span the years 1917-1986, with the bulk of the records concentrated in the period 1940-1980. The records consist of correspondence, memoranda, reports, minutes of meetings, agenda, ballots, financial records, drafts of books, articles, and lectures, testimonies, printed and near printed matter, and miscellaneous material. The collection is organized into eight series representing the structure and function of the organization, including Council of Representatives, Board of Directors, Administration, Boards and Committees, Divisions, Journals and Publications, and Affiliated Organizations, as well as a Miscellany file. The records are replete with gaps. A lack of consistency in the retirement of APA records may have contributed to the absence of material regarding certain periods or subjects. Many divisions and committees did not retire their records to the Library of Congress, preferring the Akron University Psychological Archives in Akron, Ohio. The records of the APA held by that institution should be consulted where gaps exist here.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms009030.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T14:00:06</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms009116.2</id>
    <title>George E. Agree Papers</title>
    <updated>2012-02-16T13:15:26</updated>
    <summary>The papers of George E. Agree (1921-2001) span the years 1961-2001 and consist of congressional testimony, correspondence, minutes, press material, reports, and writings pertaining to Agree&#x2019;s career as a political scientist. The collection documents Agree&#x2019;s involvement in the American Political Foundation, the National Committee for an Effective Congress, and the National Endowment for Democracy. Additional material covers Agree&#x2019;s work on election campaign finance reform, including several articles he authored on the subject. Miscellaneous material includes biographical information, proposals, and writings.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms009116.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:43</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms008048.2</id>
    <title>American Studies Association Records</title>
    <updated>2012-02-16T13:15:26</updated>
    <summary>Part I of the records of the American Studies Association spans the years 1946-2003, with the bulk of the material dating from 1965 to 1980. The records are organized in an Administrative File and American Quarterly series. The Administrative File contains correspondence, committee material, minutes and notes of meetings, financial records, and program information. Files dedicated to committees chronicle the history of the organization and the development of a definition of &#x201C;American studies.&#x201D; The files also include items from the Radical Caucus of the ASA, a short-lived ad hoc committee. Membership files and surveys illustrate the membership of the organization, and program surveys document the teaching of American studies.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms008048.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T14:02:53</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/eadmss.ms009104.2</id>
    <title>William Henry Allison Diaries</title>
    <updated>2012-02-16T13:15:26</updated>
    <summary>The papers of William Henry Allison (1870-1941) span the years 1868-1940 and consist entirely of diaries and an index to these volumes. A diary kept by Allison&#x2019;s grandmother, Mary Ireland Allison, covers the period 1868-1869. Allison's diaries chronicle his daily activities as a historian at Pacific Theological Seminary, Bryn Mawr College, Colgate University, and other universities, as a clergyman at Penacook Baptist Church, Concord, New Hampshire, 1899-1902, and as a consultant in church history to the Library of Congress, 1930-1941.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmss.ms009104.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T14:03:14</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mbrsrs/eadmbrs.rs009006.2</id>
    <title>Joseph Nathan Kane Collection</title>
    <updated>2012-01-19T20:07:05</updated>
    <summary>The Joseph Nathan Kane Collection consists of original and preservation recordings of the radio program Famous First Facts, scripts and publicity materials from the program, and a vintage 1930s microphone.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmbrs.rs009006.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:21</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mbrsrs/eadmbrs.rs009003.2</id>
    <title>Sound Recordings and Other Material from the Zbigniew Brzezinski Papers</title>
    <updated>2012-01-19T20:07:03</updated>
    <summary>The Carter Administration series consists of recorded speeches and interviews, accompanying transcripts, and other material related to Brzezinski's tenure as national security advisor in President Jimmy Carter's administration.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmbrs.rs009003.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:17</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu011010.2</id>
    <title>Max Rudolf Papers </title>
    <updated>2012-01-19T20:07:03</updated>
    <summary>The Max Rudolf Papers span the period 1922-1993, with the majority of materials dating from his professional period in the United States, 1945-1992. The collection is arranged in three series: Correspondence, 1922-1993; Photographs, 1952 and undated; and Metropolitan Opera Annual Files, 1946-1975.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu011010.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-08-19T16:21:20</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu011017.2</id>
    <title>Gerry Mulligan Collection </title>
    <updated>2012-01-19T20:07:02</updated>
    <summary>The manuscripts in the Gerry Mulligan Collection were processed in a manner that complements the arrangement of the original Gerry Mulligan Music Library.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu011017.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-10-25T14:51:36</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mbrsrs/eadmbrs.rs009004.2</id>
    <title>Allen Prescott Collection</title>
    <updated>2012-01-19T20:07:02</updated>
    <summary>The Allen Prescott Collection consists of sound recordings, photographs, and printed materials pertaining to Prescott&#x2019;s career as a radio personality during the early 1930s to 1970.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmbrs.rs009004.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:09</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu007004.2</id>
    <title>Geraldine Farrar Collection</title>
    <updated>2012-01-19T20:07:01</updated>
    <summary>Biographical Materials series in the collection include drafts in several versions for Farrar's autobiography Such Sweet Compulsion. Additionally, the Writings series contains a lecture titled "Vocal Treatise with record illustrations" as well as the typescript for a book of vocal exercises. These vocal treatises are complemented by three books of Farrar's vocal exercises dating from 1923 to 1925. Also of note are Farrar's lectures, "The Effects of War on Music," and "Music in a War-torn World," both written during World War II. The writings also include numerous versions of a lecture on the history of music titled "Music through the ages." The majority of the lectures date from the years following Farrar's retirement from her opera career in 1922.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu007004.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:57</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/eadafc.af010002.2</id>
    <title>James Madison Carpenter Collection</title>
    <updated>2012-01-19T20:07:00</updated>
    <summary>The James Madison Carpenter Collection spans the years 1928-1987, with the largest portion dated 1928-1935. It is arranged into two groups or series. Series I, the bulk of the collection, consists of the materials purchased from Carpenter by the American Folklife Center, including manuscripts, sound recordings, and graphic materials. The entire collection represents the results of Carpenter's fieldwork, his subsequent work on the collection, and the documentation of other professional activities. Series II consists of material about the collection, primarily generated by the American Folklife Center. It includes manuscript material, sound recordings, and graphic materials.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadafc.af010002.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-10-13T15:15:52</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/eadafc.af007004.2</id>
    <title> Working in Paterson Project Collection </title>
    <updated>2012-01-19T20:07:00</updated>
    <summary>The Working in Paterson Project Collection consists of manuscript materials, sound recordings, graphic materials, and artifacts collected during the Working in Paterson Project conducted by the American Folklife Center in 1994. The study was part of the federal Urban History Initiative (UHI) program sponsored in Congress by U.S. Senator Frank R. Lautenberg and administered by the National Park Service's Mid-Atlantic Regional Office. The four-month project, conducted between June and September 1994, explored occupational heritage and culture in Paterson, New Jersey, a city that is considered the cradle of the Industrial Revolution in America. The goal of the project was to examine how the idea of work intersects with other themes, such as family, ethnicity, gender, neighborhood, and change over time. The Paterson community yielded several additional themes that reflect both the history of industry in the United States and the specific experience of Patersonians. These themes include the continuity and change of manufacturing over time; the manufacturing process; the textile industry; industrial architecture; the impact of labor unions; diversity in the workplace; the ethnography of Watson Machine International; Paterson's distinctive food tradition, the Hot Texas Wiener; the role of agricultural occupations in urban areas; and work, family, and home.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadafc.af007004.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:53</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/eadafc.af005003.2</id>
    <title> Art Rosenbaum Georgia Folklore Collection </title>
    <updated>2012-01-19T20:06:59</updated>
    <summary>Art Rosenbaum collected these field recordings in north and coastal Georgia between 1976 and 1983. They include many genres of instrumental and vocal folk music and, in addition, oral history interviews with some performers. These recordings were made in homes, churches, and at festivals with the intent of: 1) preserving through duplication the content of deteriorating tapes of local performing traditions; 2) making these recordings accessible to a wider public; and 3) ensuring the continuity of the musical traditions of these performers' ancestors.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadafc.af005003.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:52</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/eadafc.af007003.2</id>
    <title> Italian-Americans in the West Project Collection </title>
    <updated>2012-01-19T20:06:59</updated>
    <summary>Italian-Americans in the West Project Collection contains the sound recordings, photographs, video recordings, fieldnotes, publications, ephemera, and accompanying manuscript materials associated with the American Folklife Center's Italian-Americans in the West project. This project was part of the Center's commemoration of the 500th anniversary of the voyage of Christopher Columbus, which was an element of a larger program on the Quincentenary sponsored by the Library of Congress. The purpose of the three-year field research project was to document aspects of traditional cultural expression of Italian Americans in the western United States.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadafc.af007003.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:52</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/eadafc.af002001.2</id>
    <title>Kenneth M. Bilby Jamaican Maroon Collection</title>
    <updated>2012-01-19T20:06:59</updated>
    <summary>The Kenneth M. Bilby Jamaican Maroon Collection consists of manuscript materials, audio recordings, and video recordings. The materials span the years 1977-1979 and 1991. Bilby conducted fieldwork in Jamaica from 1977 to 1978 as part of his research for a master's thesis in anthropology from Wesleyan University. His focus was on the traditional religion and music of the Jamaican Maroons (descendants of runaway slaves) who live in Moore Town, Scott's Hall, Accompong, and Charles Town. The collection is the result of a 1983 Library audiotape duplication project and a 1994 videotape duplication project, and includes a manuscript copy of Bilby's master's thesis. Bilby and another researcher, Diana Baird N'Diaye, recorded the Maroons in October 1991 as part of their fieldwork in Jamaica prior to the 1992 Maroon Program of the Smithsonian Festival of American Folklife. Duplicates of videotapes made in 1991 further complement the materials. </summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadafc.af002001.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:53</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/eadafc.af010005.2</id>
    <title> Square Dance Legislation Collection</title>
    <updated>2012-01-19T20:06:59</updated>
    <summary>The Square Dance Legislation Collection consists primarily of correspondence, copies of proposed legislation, newspaper clippings, magazine articles, and other publications that document the history of legislative efforts to designate the square dance as the national folk dance. The collection also includes material concerning related efforts at the state level. It spans the years 1975 to 1995, with the largest portion concerning the public hearing on House Resolution 1706 in 1984. National Western-style square dance organizations have fostered a movement to add square dance to the list of national symbols. Between 1965 and 1995, more than thirty bills were introduced at the federal level. Their efforts also have focused on passing legislation at the state level; by 1995 at least 17 states had designated square dance as the official folk dance of that state. </summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadafc.af010005.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-03-25T13:30:39</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/eadafc.af006007.2</id>
    <title> Penne Laingen Yellow Ribbon Collection </title>
    <updated>2012-01-19T20:06:58</updated>
    <summary>In 1979, Penne (Penelope) Laingen tied a yellow ribbon around a tree in front of her Bethesda, Maryland home when her husband, Bruce, was among those taken hostage in the United States Embassy in Tehran, Iran. The Laingens donated this yellow ribbon to the Library of Congress in 1991. The collection contains sound recordings and a photograph from that donation ceremony. Other recordings include an interview with Bruce and Penne Laingen conducted by American Folklife Center reference specialist, Gerald E. Parsons, on April 15, 1991. During the interview, the Laingens discussed their experiences during the hostage crisis and their use of the yellow ribbon and the symbolic significance it acquired. The collection also contains photographs of the Laingens taken during this interview and photographs of yellow ribbon displays during the Persian Gulf War in 1991.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadafc.af006007.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:50</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/eadafc.af007002.2</id>
    <title>Harold C. Conklin Philippine Collection</title>
    <updated>2012-01-19T20:06:57</updated>
    <summary>There are approximately 140,000 Ifugao living in scattered districts over some 170 square miles in northern Luzon. They are agrarian farmers who have perfected a system of sustainable rice terracing uniquely suited to the heavy rainstorms and rugged terrain of northern Luzon, Philippines. In their tribal society, rice is more than a basic sustenance; it also serves as a medium of exchange and a signifier of status. Rituals, ceremonies, and events are tightly interwoven into the Ifugao people's daily lives. The characteristic richness and diversity of the Ifugao agriculture, religion, and music is strongly evident in The Harold C. Conklin Philippine Collection, which includes what arguably is one of the largest, most comprehensive set of audio recordings on the Ifugao in existence. It documents continuity and change in some of the most important features of Ifugao culture over the course of forty years.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadafc.af007002.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:46</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu002003.2</id>
    <title>Edison Sheet Music Collection</title>
    <updated>2012-01-19T20:06:53</updated>
    <summary>The Edison Sheet Music Collection consists chiefly of American sheet music published in the United States between the years 1830-1930. While a significant minority of the music in the collection is instrumental music, the vast majority is for voice and piano. Notable in this collection are imprints from California dating from before 1850, first editions by Irving Berlin and others, and many European imprints among the instrumental pieces.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu002003.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:17</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/eadafc.af011018.2</id>
    <title>1991 Neptune Plaza Concert Series Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-12-16T15:01:45</updated>
    <summary>The 1991 Neptune Plaza Concert Series Collection consists of manuscript and print materials, sound recordings, graphic materials, and moving images that document the 1991 concert series sponsored by the American Folklife Center. The annual series, which began in 1977, features the presentation of folk traditions from many cultures.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadafc.af011018.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-12-16T15:01:45</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/eadafc.af011017.2</id>
    <title>1990 Neptune Plaza Concert Series Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-12-16T15:01:45</updated>
    <summary>The 1990 Neptune Plaza Concert Series Collection consists of manuscript and print materials, audio recordings, graphic materials, and moving images that document the 1990 concert series sponsored by the American Folklife Center. The annual series, which began in 1977, features the presentation of folk traditions from many cultures. The concerts take place on the Neptune Plaza at the front of the Jefferson Building of the Library of Congress between April and September. Adverse weather conditions sometimes force the concerts indoors. </summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadafc.af011017.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-12-16T15:01:45</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu011020.2</id>
    <title>Luther Henderson Papers </title>
    <updated>2011-12-16T15:01:45</updated>
    <summary>The Luther Henderson Papers span from the 1930s to 2003 with the majority of the materials dating from 1960 to 1995. The collection includes music manuscripts, subject files, correspondence, business papers, financial documents, photographs, writings, posters, biographical materials, and realia.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu011020.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-12-16T15:01:45</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/eadafc.af011016.2</id>
    <title>1989 Neptune Plaza Concert Series Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-12-16T15:01:44</updated>
    <summary>The 1989 Neptune Plaza Concert Series Collection consists of manuscript and print materials, audio recordings, and graphic materials that document the 1989 concert series sponsored by the American Folklife Center. The annual series, which began in 1977, features the presentation of folk traditions from many cultures. The concerts take place on the Neptune Plaza at the front of the Jefferson Building of the Library of Congress between April and September. Adverse weather conditions sometimes force the concerts indoors. The 1989 series was produced with the assistance of the National Council for the Traditional Arts. Concerts were broadcast live on WAMU-FM, hosted by Dick Spottswood.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadafc.af011016.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-12-16T15:01:44</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/eadafc.af009001.2</id>
    <title>Lands' End All-American Quilt Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-12-16T15:01:44</updated>
    <summary>The Lands' End All-American Quilt Collection consists of visual images, essays, entry forms, and administrative materials from three quilt contests held in 1992, 1994, and 1996. The collection was donated to the American Folklife Center by Lands' End in 1997. The 1996 national first place winning quilt, made by Candy Goff of Montana, was displayed at the reception to celebrate the 20th anniversary of the establishment of the American Folklife Center at the Library of Congress in September 1996. </summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadafc.af009001.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:51</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu002009.2</id>
    <title>Hodges Family Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-11-18T20:00:43</updated>
    <summary>The Hodges Family Collection contains manuscript and printed music, writings, and other materials compiled and collected by Edward Hodges (1792-1867) and subsequently by his son, John Sebastian Bach Hodges (1830-1915). Soon after the collection arrived at the Library of Congress Music Division, approximately two-thirds of the bound volumes of the collection were cataloged and dispersed both throughout the Division and to other collections of the Library. No attempt to reconstruct the original contents of the collection has been made; the present finding aid serves as a guide primarily to the one-third of the original gift that has remained uncataloged. The only catalogued items included here are music manuscripts and writings of Edward Hodges himself and the 16 bound volumes M1.H7 (described below), as well as various other appropriate materials that had received only minimal cataloging. These items have been reunited with the uncataloged items in the Hodges collection in order to facilitate their access.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu002009.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:22</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/eadafc.af011002.2</id>
    <title>1995 Neptune Plaza Concert Series Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-11-18T20:00:40</updated>
    <summary>The 1995 Neptune Plaza Concert Series Collection consists of manuscript and print materials, sound recordings, graphic materials, and moving images that document the 1995 concert series sponsored by the American Folklife Center. The annual series, which began in 1977, features the presentation of folk traditions from many cultures. The concerts take place on the Neptune Plaza at the front of the Jefferson Building of the Library of Congress between April and September. Adverse weather conditions sometimes force the concerts indoors.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadafc.af011002.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-09-22T16:17:31</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu002006.2</id>
    <title>Aaron Copland Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-11-18T20:00:35</updated>
    <summary>The Aaron Copland Collection consists of published and unpublished musical scores by Aaron Copland and other composers, correspondence, writings, biographical material, datebooks, journals, professional papers including legal and financial material, photographs, awards, art work, and books. The collection spans 1841 to 1991 and covers six aspects of Copland's life -- composer, performer, teacher, writer, conductor and administrator for various organizations -- from about 1911, when he penned his first musical composition I'm On My Way to Mandalay, to 1990, the year of his death. The collection has been organized into thirteen major categories -- Music, Writings&amp;Oral Presentations, Diaries, Correspondence, Professional Papers, Subject File, Scrapbooks, Biography, Awards, Art, Photographs, Victor Kraft Material and Books.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu002006.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:26</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu011015.2</id>
    <title>Herman Langinger Music Publishing Files </title>
    <updated>2011-10-25T14:51:38</updated>
    <summary>The Herman Langinger Music Publishing Files contain materials accrued from 1927 to 1955 while Langinger worked as an engraver and publisher at his own Golden West Music Press in Hollywood, Calif. Most of the materials are related to the production of Henry Cowell's quarterly publication New Music. The collection includes holograph manuscript scores, edited score paste-ups, negative and positive proof copies, printed editions of New Music, financial receipts, notes/corrections, and correspondence (often from major composers) relating to publication. Similar materials exist for Langinger's other engraving commitments, notably Delkas Music Publishing Company and Affiliated Musicians, Inc., both in Los Angeles, Calif. The files contain works by many leading 20th century composers, such as John Cage, Charles Ives, Carl Ruggles, Mario Castelnuovo-Tedesco, Ernst Toch, Edgar Var&#xE8;se, and Arnold Schoenberg. Represented as well are Latin American composers, namely Carlos Ch&#xE1;vez (stemming from Cowell's interest in pan-American music) and various European and Soviet composers.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu011015.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-09-22T16:17:42</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu011013.2</id>
    <title>Artur Schnabel Collection </title>
    <updated>2011-10-25T14:51:37</updated>
    <summary>The Artur Schnabel Collection primarily consists of music manuscript scores of Schnabel&#x2019;s compositions. These thirty-seven manuscripts are all, with the exception of a single score in a copyist&#x2019;s hand (for the song "Dieses ist ein rechter Morgen," op. 11, no. 5), in Schnabel&#x2019;s hand, and represent his compositional essays in a variety of genres, from solo song (voice and piano) to symphonic works. In addition, the collection contains holograph manuscript scores of each of Schnabel&#x2019;s three symphonies.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu011013.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-09-22T16:17:42</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu011014.2</id>
    <title>Mary Virginia Foreman Le Garrec Collection of Artur Schnabel Materials</title>
    <updated>2011-10-25T14:51:37</updated>
    <summary>The Mary Virginia Foreman Le Garrec Collection of Artur Schnabel Materials consists of material donated to the Library in 1997 by Le Garrec, who was Schnabel's student and confidante. The collection includes published music scores by Schnabel as well as by other composers, some of which contain annotations and performance indications in the hands of Schnabel, Le Garrec, and others. In addition, the collection contains Schnabel's correspondence with music figures such as Clifford Curzon, Rudolf Firku&#x161;n&#xFD; and Le Garrec; and Le Garrec&#x2019;s correspondence with, among others, Pierre Fournier, Ren&#xE9; Liebowitz, Leopold Mannes, and Dmitri Mitropoulos. The collection also includes writings by both Schnabel and Le Garrec; concert programs featuring Schnabel as both pianist and composer; biographical material; press clippings, published articles, and monographs regarding Schnabel and his circle; books; photographs; and other iconography.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu011014.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-10-25T14:51:37</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu011016.2</id>
    <title>Jonathan Larson Papers</title>
    <updated>2011-10-25T14:51:36</updated>
    <summary>The Jonathan Larson Papers, spanning the years 1978-1996, came to the Library well-organized and accompanied by a detailed appraisal and inventory. The papers are organized in five series: Projects, Biographical Materials, Photographs, Electronic Files, and Books. The "Projects" series contains materials for musicals, musical revues, club acts, films, and dance works. These files may include any combination of notes, research materials, correspondence, scripts, script pages, lyric sheets and sketches, musical sketches and scores, notes and sketches for designs, production materials, programs and press materials, and other miscellaneous items. The "Projects" series is organized first by title, then chronologically by year, where possible, to reflect Larson's own arrangement. Cross references for variant titles are inserted in the container list.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu011016.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-10-25T14:51:36</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mbrsrs/eadmbrs.rs005002.2</id>
    <title>Columbia Records Paperwork Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-10-25T14:51:34</updated>
    <summary>The Columbia Records Paperwork Collection spans the years 1923 to 1964 and contains materials such as record label orders, record label copy sheets, press release information, recording studio job sheets, and cut-out project information (describing records to be cut out of the catalog). Many of the papers, if not the whole collection, appear to have come from the Columbia Records pressing plant in Bridgeport, Connecticut.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmbrs.rs005002.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-09-22T16:17:23</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu002007.2</id>
    <title>Newland/Zeuner Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-09-22T16:17:44</updated>
    <summary>The Newland/Zeuner Collection constitutes the working library of professional musician William A. Newland, who was active in many different musical circles in 19th-century Philadelphia. It consists almost exclusively of music, in both manuscript and printed form, and reflects the diversity of sacred and secular musical activity in America in the late-18th and early-19th century.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu002007.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:21</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu002004.2</id>
    <title>Jerome Kern Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-09-22T16:17:43</updated>
    <summary>The Jerome Kern Collection consists primarily of Show Music (Series I). The music in the collection includes a number of holograph sketches and scores, but the majority of the music is not in Kern's hand; however, much of this music does contain annotations by Kern.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu002004.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:19</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu004007.2</id>
    <title>Edward and Clara Steuermann Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-09-22T16:17:41</updated>
    <summary>The Edward and Clara Steuermann Collection consists primarily of the music (both manuscript and printed) and writings of Edward Steuermann, and the correspondence of both Edward and Clara Steuermann. The date span of the collection is from 1922 to 1981, the bulk of the materials dating from the 1930's to the 1970's.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu004007.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:17</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu004006.2</id>
    <title>Carrie Jacobs-Bond Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-09-22T16:17:40</updated>
    <summary>Carrie Jacobs-Bond (1861-1946) is known primarily as a composer and performer of popular sentimental song. Her most widely recognized compositions include I Love You Truly (1901), A Perfect Day (1910), and God Remembers When the World Forgets (1913). The most impressive portion of the collection is the music manuscripts. Only a handful of Bond's 200-plus compositions are represented in the collections sixty-seven manuscripts, however eighteen of these are holographs. Included in the holographs are two of the songs mentioned above.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu004006.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:16</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu010020.2</id>
    <title>Ethel L. Voynich Papers </title>
    <updated>2011-09-22T16:17:40</updated>
    <summary>The Ethel L. Voynich Papers span the period 1835 to 1948, with the majority of the materials dating from 1928-1948. Voynich's musical compositions, based principally on sacred or poetic texts, are represented by holograph manuscript scores, sketches, lyric sheets, and notes. Works are arranged alphabetically by title, with sources of texts identified if possible. The remaining materials consist of subject files on musicological topics and a handful of programs. Included is documentation of Voynich's studies with musicologist Josef Chominski, work done at the Pius X School of Liturgical Music in New York, research conducted at the New York Public Library, and her associations with notable Gloucester composer-poet Ivor Gurney.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu010020.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:14</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu010011.2</id>
    <title>Ludwig Zenk Music Manuscripts </title>
    <updated>2011-09-22T16:17:40</updated>
    <summary>The Ludwig Zenk Music Manuscripts consist of holograph manuscripts, sketches, and printed scores of compositions that date from 1930 to 1947. Prominent works include Klaviersonate, op. 1, no. 1 and Trakl Lieder, op. 9, settings of texts from Georg Trakl&#x2019;s Gesang zur Nacht and other poems. In addition, the collection includes Streichquartett, op.2, no. 1, Klaviersonate, op. 4, no. 2, and scores in varying states of completion for a variety of instrumental and vocal works. Compositions are arranged first by opus number, then alphabetically by title where there is no opus number. All manuscripts are in the hand of the composer unless otherwise noted. The "Miscellaneous Materials" contain two photographs of an unidentified sculpted bust and Zenk's second prize certificate from the 1947 Gesellschaft der Musikfreunde competition. </summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu010011.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:12</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu010030.2</id>
    <title>Billy May Arrangements </title>
    <updated>2011-09-22T16:17:40</updated>
    <summary>The Billy May Arrangements principally consist of holograph or photocopied manuscript scores, parts, lead sheets, and sketches for works created between 1939 and 1995. Additional materials include printed scores, part changes, film cues, and a handful of counterpoint exercises. Although May worked almost exclusively as an arranger for long periods throughout his career, he did compose original music, and several of these titles are represented in this collection. I Taut I Taw a Puddy Tat, Front Page Rag, and his film score for Sergeants Three are notable examples. Titles and cross-references are arranged alphabetically and standardized according to Jack Mirtle's The Music of Billy May: a Discography (1998). Part sets are complete unless indicated otherwise. </summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu010030.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-12-20T20:06:56</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu009009.2</id>
    <title>William Remsen Strickland Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-09-22T16:17:39</updated>
    <summary>The William Remsen Strickland Collection spans the period 1926-1991; the bulk of the materials date from 1946-1970. The collection includes correspondence, concert programs, publicity materials, newspaper and magazine clippings, music manuscripts, printed scores, articles, speeches and notes, photographs, scrapbooks, datebooks, journals, graphs, and recordings.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu009009.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:08</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu010006.2</id>
    <title>Rudolf Kolisch Collection </title>
    <updated>2011-09-22T16:17:39</updated>
    <summary>The Rudolf Kolisch Collection contains thirty-one items, principally manuscript correspondence, that provide insight into the professional relationship between Kolisch and composers Arnold Schoenberg, Alban Berg, and Anton Webern, from 1921-1943. The Musical Analysis and Examples series includes materials related to Berg's Lyric suite and String quartet, op. 3. The Correspondence series consists of postcards and letters, chiefly from Webern to Kolisch, that discuss compositional progress and upcoming performances. Among the works mentioned are Webern's String trio, op. 20, String quartet, op. 28, Six bagatelles, op. 9, F&#xFC;nf S&#xE4;tze, op. 5, Symphony, op. 21, and Variations for piano, op. 27, as well as various compositions by Schoenberg, Berg, and Beethoven. </summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu010006.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:10</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu010007.2</id>
    <title>USIA Artistic Ambassador Program Musical Commissions </title>
    <updated>2011-09-22T16:17:39</updated>
    <summary>The musical works commissioned for the USIA Artistic Ambassador Program date from 1982-1988. The "Music Manuscripts" series contains holograph manuscripts and/or sketches for all thirteen commissioned pieces, with Bacon's "Gunnison River" being the only exception. Two additional works commissioned by the USIA prior to 1982, but not for the Artistic Ambassador Program, are also included. Lukas Foss&#x2019; Fanfare was commissioned to commemorate the 50th anniversary of the Turkish Republic and was performed by the Presidential Symphony of Ankara in Istanbul with Foss conducting on June 28, 1973. Leo Smit&#x2019;s Symphony of dances and songs was commissioned to commemorate the 100th anniversary of the establishment of U.S./Serbian diplomatic relations and was performed by the Belgrade Philharmonic with Smit conducting on November 6, 1981.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu010007.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:10</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu010015.2</id>
    <title>Henryk Szeryng Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-09-22T16:17:38</updated>
    <summary>The Henrk Szeryng Collection documents the career of a great violinist who was also active as a teacher, a patron of the arts, and a diplomat. The bulk of the materials are Szeryng's collected musical scores, but also included are personal papers relating to activities other than musical performance. Various teaching and master-class materials in the collection date from his many years as an educator, and a number of speeches and writings reflect his active role as a public figure. Szeryng's generosity in supporting the arts and other worthy causes, as demonstrated by his donation of several valuable violins for use by promising young violinists and by his many benefit performances, is also well documented in the biographical articles and interviews of the collection.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu010015.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:05</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu011011.2</id>
    <title>Harold Spivacke Collection </title>
    <updated>2011-09-22T16:17:37</updated>
    <summary>The Harold Spivacke Collection spans the years 1923 to 1984, with the bulk of the materials dating from 1930 to 1978. The collection reflects the life of a musicologist, music librarian, and administrator of the Music Division of the Library of Congress. It includes his doctoral dissertation and student notebooks, correspondence with composers and colleagues in the fields of musicology and librarianship, awards and honorary degrees, manuscript and printed music, programs, clippings, artwork, photographs, and papers and printed matter from his numerous associations.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu011011.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-09-22T16:17:37</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu009012.2</id>
    <title>Artur Rodzinski Collection </title>
    <updated>2011-09-22T16:17:37</updated>
    <summary>The Artur Rodzinski Collection focuses on Rodzinski&#x2019;s professional work as a conductor and his personal life in the United States, Europe and Latin America. The collection covers Rodzinski&#x2019;s performances (live, radio and sound recordings), schedules, and biographical information. The materials primarily consist of correspondence, annotated music, magazine articles, newspaper clippings, legal documents, programs and advertisements. Other items include: photographs, notes, an address book, announcements, bills, brochures, catalogs and schedules. Most of the collection is in English, with a significant amount of material in Polish. Other languages include: Italian, Russian, German, French, Spanish, Hebrew and Japanese. A portion of the collection comes from Rodzinski&#x2019;s wife, Halina, including items relating to her book, personal correspondence and articles published after the conductor&#x2019;s death. Printed music that was not annotated was removed from the collection and is cataloged separately in the Library of Congress Music Division&#x2019;s general collections.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu009012.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:03</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu011005.2</id>
    <title>Arne Oldberg Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-09-22T16:17:36</updated>
    <summary>Oldberg's musical oeuvre, as represented in the collection, includes seven symphonies, three piano concertos, several large orchestral works, chamber works, solo piano pieces as well as vocal works. These works span his student days to just before his death and represent, by far, the largest series in the collection. Most of the works contain opus numbers but the numbering system is not always consistent; several pieces share opus numbers, e.g.: the Quintet, 2 violins, viola, cello, piano, op. 24, c# minor and Concertino for piano and chamber orchestra, op. 24; the Sinfonia op. 48 and the Sonata for violin/cello and piano op. 48 and op. 48a; as well as the Ballade op. 53 and the Trois Chansons Fran&#xE7;aises, op. 53. An index to the musical compositions and opus numbers is found in appendix A.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu011005.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-05-23T14:32:22</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu010017.2</id>
    <title>Von Tilzer / Gumm Collection </title>
    <updated>2011-09-22T16:17:36</updated>
    <summary>The Von Tilzer / Gumm Collection consists of both personal and professional papers of composer and music publisher Harry Von Tilzer and his brother, H. Harold Gumm, who was both a lawyer and an agent cum producer in the entertainment business. The date span of the collection is from 1878 to 1959, with the bulk of the materials dating between the early 1900s and the 1940s. Because Harold Gumm served as executor of Harry Von Tilzer's estate and took over the Harry Von Tilzer Music Publishing Co. when Von Tilzer died in 1946 (after having served as attorney for the publishing house for several decades), the records of the HVTMPC are inextricably combined not only with Harry Von Tilzer's papers but also with Gumm's papers and those of Goldie&amp;Gumm. Various papers of Harry's other brothers also appear in the collection. Therefore, although the collection has been organized into traditional series according to type of materials, within each series type the materials are divided into the following categories by originator (where necessary): Harry Von Tilzer, Estate of Harry Von Tilzer, Harry Von Tilzer Music Publishing Co., [Other Von Tilzer brothers], H. Harold Gumm, William V. Goldie, and Goldie&amp;Gumm.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu010017.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-10-29T17:55:26</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu011012.2</id>
    <title>Charles Tournemire Collection </title>
    <updated>2011-09-22T16:17:36</updated>
    <summary>The collection primarily consists of manuscript and printed music, but also includes librettos, a scrapbook, books, and one issue of a journal.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu011012.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-09-22T16:17:36</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu010002.2</id>
    <title>Inter-American Music Festival Foundation Papers </title>
    <updated>2011-09-22T16:17:35</updated>
    <summary>This collection contains concert programs, publicity materials, clippings, and correspondence from the nearly 25-year history of the Inter-American Music Festival Foundation. Harold Boxer, chief of the Music Branch of Voice of America, Guillermo Espinosa, chief of the Music Division of the Organization of American States, and Harold Spivake, chief of the Music Division of the Library of Congress were responsible for incorporating the foundation in 1965. The collection contains correspondence from Espinosa and Boxer, among others. The Library lacks materials for festivals one and eleven.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu010002.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:00</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu004010.2</id>
    <title>National Flute Association, Inc. Archives</title>
    <updated>2011-09-22T16:17:35</updated>
    <summary>Part I</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu004010.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:59</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu011004.2</id>
    <title>Louise Talma Papers</title>
    <updated>2011-09-22T16:17:34</updated>
    <summary>Music materials from the Louise Talma Papers span the period 1875 to 1996, with the majority dating from 1928 to 1994. These consist chiefly of holograph manuscript scores, sketches, tone rows, and photo-reproduced manuscripts bearing annotations in the composer's hand. Many works are accompanied by errata, correspondence, programs, notes, and other items of interest. Talma's tendency to date sketches and manuscripts at different stages in her creative process is useful for tracing her compositional shift from neoclassicism to serialism and atonality. Her final work, Spacings (1994), was completed at Yaddo only two years before her death and marked the end of a nearly seventy-year career as a composer. Notable manuscripts in the collection include holograph scores for the opera The Alcestiad (1958) and the oratorio The Divine Flame (1946-1948), Four-Handed Fun (1943), Piano Sonata no. 1 (1943), and her award-winning Toccata for Orchestra (1944).</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu011004.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-05-23T14:32:21</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu011003.2</id>
    <title>Tommy Newsom Arrangements </title>
    <updated>2011-09-22T16:17:34</updated>
    <summary>Tommy Newsom Arrangements contain dance band, symphonic orchestra, and small ensemble musical arrangements for 267 works. These include manuscripts, printed copies, and photocopies for both full scores and orchestral parts. While the collection spans Newsom's fifty-year career, from 1947 dance band arrangements to pieces for trumpeter Doc Severinsen's recordings in 1999, most of the music dates from his thirty-year stint on the Tonight Show. Many of the selections were arranged for featured performers, such as vocalists Vic Damone, Crystal Gayle, Patti Page, Paul Anka, Joe Williams, Glen Campbell, and Diahann Carroll; trumpeter Doc Severinsen; drummers Buddy Rich, Louis Bellson, and Duffy Jackson; trombonist Urbie Green; saxophonist Boots Randolph; and Newsom on tenor sax. A few arrangements in the collection are not by Newsom and are credited accordingly.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu011003.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-04-25T17:56:05</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu009015.2</id>
    <title>Gilbert Miller Collection </title>
    <updated>2011-09-22T16:17:34</updated>
    <summary>The Gilbert Miller Collection spans the period 1921-1967. The bulk of the materials date from 1932-1955. The collection includes correspondence, contracts, scripts, speeches, scenic floor plans, scenic and costume renderings, clippings, programs, and other materials related to Gilbert Miller&#x2019;s life and career. As a representation of Miller&#x2019;s distinguished career, the materials provide insights into his work as a manager, producer, and advocate for the theater.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu009015.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:58</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu009008.2</id>
    <title>Cole Porter Collection </title>
    <updated>2011-09-22T16:17:33</updated>
    <summary>The Cole Porter Collection at the Library of Congress provides the researcher with an invaluable look at Porter's creative process and represents a large percentage of his output, particularly of his later works. Eighteen shows are included in the collection representing twenty-one productions, including film versions of stage works. Over 280 song titles are represented, some as incomplete lyric sketches only.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu009008.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:58</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu003013.2</id>
    <title>Randolph S. Rothschild Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-09-22T16:17:32</updated>
    <summary>The Randolph S. Rothschild Collections consists primarily of music (manuscript, facsimile, and printed) and accompanying correspondence, programs, and reviews. The collection spans the years 1942 to 1992, with the bulk of the materials dating from 1973 to 1985.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu003013.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:54</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu005001.2</id>
    <title>Nikolai Lopatnikoff Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-09-22T16:17:32</updated>
    <summary>The works and writings of Nikolai Lopatnikoff (1903-1976), composer, pianist and teacher, reflect a profound understanding of musical aesthetics and of twentieth century trends in music. Although less widely performed today, Lopatnikoff's musical works were well received by critics and public alike during his lifetime. Incorporating elements of various contemporary styles, Lopatnikoff forged a musical language characterized by a constantly shifting tonality, motivic development and a concise, tightly-woven structure, at once infused with a profoundly Russian emotional quality.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu005001.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:55</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu004008.2</id>
    <title>Ragheb Moftah Collection of Coptic Orthodox Liturgical Chants and Hymns</title>
    <updated>2011-09-22T16:17:32</updated>
    <summary>The Ragheb Moftah Collection of Coptic Orthodox Liturgical Chants and Hymns consists of transcriptions of Coptic chant music by Ernest Newlandsmith (compiled 1926-1936) and Margit Toth (begun 1970). Both contain transcriptions of the Liturgy of St. Basil. Also part of the collection, but housed in the Motion Picture, Broadcasting and Recorded and Sound Division, are audio tapes of Coptic chant music recorded by Moftah between 1940 and 1985, with the bulk recorded in 1965 and 1975-1985. Marian Robertson Wilson created a guide to the audiotapes in 1996, which consists of transcriptions, transliterations and translations into English of the texts sung on the tapes. Wilson also devised a new order for the pieces on the tapes, putting them in a more logical order, as used in the context of the liturgy. The most important part of the correspondence consists of letters from Ernest Newlandsmith to Ragheb Moftah concerning their collaboration.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu004008.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:53</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu004009.2</id>
    <title>Charles Mingus Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-09-22T16:17:30</updated>
    <summary>The Charles Mingus Collection covers the music career of this celebrated African American jazz musician/composer from about 1939, the year he composed What Love and Half Mast Inhibition, to his death on January 5, 1979. Originally estimated to have an item count of less than 10,000, the collection actually contains nearly 15,000 items. The Mingus Collection represents the first multi-format jazz collection processed in the Library of Congress Music Division to include holograph music manuscripts and sound recordings.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu004009.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:48</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu003012.2</id>
    <title>Moldenhauer Archives at the Library of Congress</title>
    <updated>2011-09-22T16:17:29</updated>
    <summary>The Moldenhauer Archives at the Library of Congress consist primarily of music (both manuscript and printed), correspondence, photographs, sound recordings, books, newspaper clippings, printed programs, drawings, and engravings. The Archives span years from the Middle Ages to the present, and include documents of composers, musicians, and literary figures, among others.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu003012.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:46</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu006003.2</id>
    <title>Pola Nirenska Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-09-22T16:17:28</updated>
    <summary>The Pola Nirenska Collection consists primarily of biographical materials, correspondence, choreographic notes, programs, publicity, scrapbooks, photographic materials, art work, and audiovisual materials. Excluding published books and recordings, the collection spans the years 1927 to 1992. The bulk of the documents date from the 1950s to the 1990s -- the period of Nirenska's career in the United States -- but the collection contains many valuable materials from her early career in Europe.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu006003.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:44</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu003004.2</id>
    <title>Alberto Nepomuceno Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-09-22T16:17:27</updated>
    <summary>The Alberto Nepomuceno Collection reveals a major composer who was a pioneer among Brazilian musicians and who was recognized as the "father" of musical nationalism in his country. In addition to being the first to incorporate native themes and rhythms into art music in Brazil, he developed a brilliant career as a prominent teacher and theoretician, an orchestra conductor, pianist and organist, and a musical administrator.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu003004.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:35</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu002002.2</id>
    <title>Richard Rodgers Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-09-22T16:17:26</updated>
    <summary>The Richard Rodgers Collection at the Library of Congress consists predominantly of Rodgers' music holographs -- sketches, piano-vocal scores (many with lyric sheets included) and short scores. In addition, the collection includes the full scores for eight of the Rodgers and Hammerstein shows (Allegro, Carousel, Flower Drum Song, The King and I, Oklahoma, Pipe Dream, The Sound of Music, and South Pacific). The majority of these scores are in the hand of the orchestrator Robert Russell Bennett, but other orchestrators are represented and identified in this guide whenever possible. The collection also includes a small number of programs, photographs, miscellaneous papers, and a few miscellaneous items. A few items have been transferred to the Motion Picture Broadcasting and Recorded Sound Division -- Rodgers' "gold record" for The Sound of Music; two video cassettes of home movies; and one cassette tape recorded by Zoe Hyde-Thomson consisting of Rodgers' reminiscences during World War II. The two video cassettes of home movies are from the 20s&amp;30s, includes scenes w/ Larry Hart, Rodgers' family, and theatre&amp;Hollywood people, such as Fannie Brice, Edna Ferber, Dorothy Fields, Herbert Fields, Lew Fields, Charlie Ruggles, Jean Harlow, Leila Hyams, Herbert Marshall, Al Jolson, Harry Langdon, and director Lewis Milestone on the set of "Hallelujah, I'm a Bum") 2c (1 including people above, w/ Mrs. Rodgers voiceover, the 2nd showing Mrs. Rodgers&amp;her daughters, w/ no voice over), si.&amp;sd., b/w, 3/4" Videocasettes VSA0082-83.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu002002.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:35</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu002011.2</id>
    <title>Nicolas Slonimsky Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-09-22T16:17:24</updated>
    <summary>The Nicolas Slonimsky Collection contains materials collected by Slonimsky throughout his lifetime that document his life and work as musicologist, composer, conductor lecturer and author. His career as a composer and performer together with his lexicographical work, especially in compiling detailed information about the lives and works of musicians- those of the twentieth century in particular- has produced a remarkable archive of music, correspondence, memorabilia, books and related documents.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu002011.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:29</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu002008.2</id>
    <title>Serge Koussevitzky Archive</title>
    <updated>2011-09-22T16:17:22</updated>
    <summary>The Serge Koussevitzky Archive is a remarkable collection of correspondence, personal and business papers, photographs, and other materials which document some of the most significant aspects of twentieth-century music. Through his work as a conductor and publisher, and his efforts to commission new musical works, Serge Koussevitzky, director of the Boston Symphony Orchestra from 1924 until his death in 1951, maintained deep ties with many of the finest composers and musicians of the day. These figures are represented in their personal and professional affiliations with the conductor. In addition to serving as a record of Koussevitzky's life and career, the collection extensively chronicles periods in the history of organizations such as the Boston Symphony Orchestra and the Berkshire Music Center, the Koussevitzky Music Foundation, and the American International Music Fund.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu002008.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:22</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.pnp/eadpnp.pp996001.2</id>
    <title>VISUAL MATERIALS FROM THE NATIONAL ASSOCIATION FOR THE ADVANCEMENT OF COLORED PEOPLE RECORDS</title>
    <updated>2011-08-19T16:21:20</updated>
    <summary>The collection consists of approximately 5,000 items, primarily photographs and photomechanical prints reflecting many of the Association's administrative and civil rights programs. The images range in date from ca. 1838 to 1969, the bulk dating from 1944 to 1955.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadpnp.pp996001.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:18</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu004004.2</id>
    <title>William B. Bradbury Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-08-19T16:21:20</updated>
    <summary>The William B. Bradbury Collection was given to the Library of Congress in 1976 and 2000 by Joan M. Undeland, Bradbury's great-great-granddaughter. These materials complemented a number of Bradbury's holograph and first-edition printed musical scores that were given to the Library of Congress by Hubert P. Main and others earlier in the 20th century.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu004004.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:19</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu002001.2</id>
    <title>Glenn Dillard Gunn Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-08-19T16:21:18</updated>
    <summary>The Glenn Dillard Gunn Collection consists primarily of Correspondence, Photographs, and Music. The range of dates represented in the collection is 1874-1961.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu002001.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:16</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu010025.2</id>
    <title>Franko Goldman Family Papers </title>
    <updated>2011-08-19T16:21:18</updated>
    <summary>The Franko Goldman Family Papers are chiefly related to the professional lives of brothers Sam and Nahan Franko, their nephew Edwin Franko Goldman and his son Richard Franko Goldman. The Correspondence series is the largest portion of the collection and includes letters to and from Percy Grainger, Henry Cowell, including several letters he wrote from San Quentin, Wallingford Riegger, Yehudi Menuhin, Aaron Copland, Darius Milhaud, Douglas Moore, Leo Sowerby, and Edgard Var&#xE8;se. The Writings series includes a typescript of the unpublished autobiography of Edwin Franko Goldman, two holograph manuscripts written by Edwin on building band programs and starting a band school, and several articles by Richard Franko Goldman. The Photographs series contains photographs of Richard Franko Goldman, the Goldman Band, and various composers and musicians. Many in this latter category are inscribed to members of the Franko Goldman family and include the following individuals: Sergei Rachmaninoff, Moritz Moszkowski, Mischa Elman, Ottorino Respighi, Yehudi Menuhin, and Carlos Ch&#xE1;vez. The Scrapbook series contains six scrapbooks belonging to Sam Franko that contain manuscript notes and commentaries, programs, clippings, letters, photographs and other ephemera relating to his life and career. The Autograph Book is a velvet-coated album compiled by Richard Franko Goldman's great-aunt Lybia Franko, and contains seventy-four inscriptions and autographs of prominent musical and theatrical figures.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu010025.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-10-29T17:55:38</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu004005.2</id>
    <title>Julius Gold Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-08-19T16:21:17</updated>
    <summary>Julius Gold was a musicologist and teacher of both violin and music theory who was active in California in the first half of the 20th century. Having studied with the German theorist Bernhard Ziehn in Chicago from 1905-1910, Gold became an interpreter of Ziehn and one of his most avid apologists. Although his writings on Ziehn were never published, numerous typescripts of Gold's translations of and commentaries on Ziehn's writings are included in this collection. Gold also wrote extensively on the ecclesiastical modes, and the collection includes an abundance of writings and score examples both on modal doctrines and a wide variety of other subjects of music theory.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu004005.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:16</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu004002.2</id>
    <title>Amateur Hour Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-08-19T16:21:17</updated>
    <summary>The records of the Amateur Hour Collection consist primarily of over 7,000 applications from contestants who appeared on the Major Bowes' Original Amateur Hour radio program between 1934 and 1948. The remainder of the materials in the collection are administrative papers dating from the late 1940s and 1950s. Although these materials are only a small percentage of the admistrative papers of the organization, they are worthy of note in that they provide some insight into the way in which the Original Amateur Hour program was run. Materials relating to the Mexican version of the program, La Hora Internacional del Aficionado, are also included.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu004002.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:15</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu004003.2</id>
    <title>Harold Bauer Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-08-19T16:21:16</updated>
    <summary>The material in the Harold Bauer Collection is divided into ten sections. From a musicological perspective, the material of most notable interest is found in the Correspondence series, which includes Bauer's correspondence with many of this century's most important musical figures, such as Ernest Bloch, Nadia Boulanger, Pablo Casals, Gabriel Faur&#xE9;, Percy Grainger, Jascha Heifetz, Josef Hofmann, Gustav Holst, Vincent d'Indy, Fritz Kreisler, Charles Martin Loeffler, Pierre Monteux, Moritz Moszkowski, Vladimir de Pachmann, Ignace Jan Paderewski, Isidore Philipp, Henry Pruni&#xE8;res, Carl Ruggles, Carlos Salzedo, Gustave Schirmer, Leopold Stokowski, and Efrem Zimbalist; the Music series, which contains several holograph transcriptions and editions prepared by Bauer and others; the Iconography series, which includes both artwork and photographs, and among the latter, inscribed photographs of Ernest Bloch, Claude Debussy, Ignace Jan Paderewski, Leopold Stokowski, and Rabindranath Tagore; and the Writings by/about Bauer series, which contains articles and speeches by Bauer on a wide range of music-related topics. Also included in this collection are publicity material regarding Bauer and/or other performers, including concert programs and information about concert tours; press clippings, the majority of which are about Bauer, his performances, or about others; clippings from journals and magazines about or by Bauer; awards; and realia. The variety of material contained within this collection reflects the multi-faceted personality and diverse interests of a man devoted to the pursuit of his art, and its appreciation by its listeners.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu004003.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:14</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu010016.2</id>
    <title>Alma Gluck Scrapbooks and Other Materials </title>
    <updated>2011-08-19T16:21:16</updated>
    <summary>The Alma Gluck Scrapbooks and Other Materials span the period 1902-1940, with the majority of the materials dating from 1909-1917. Gluck's distinguished career as an operatic singer is chronicled in eleven scrapbooks filled with clippings of performance reviews and other musical activities, including recording releases with Victor Records and voice studies with Marcella Sembrich. Interspersed are articles pertaining to personal matters such as her divorce from Bernard Gluck, marriage to Efrem Zimbalist, and other subjects.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu010016.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:13</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu010003.2</id>
    <title>Eric Johnson Collection of Ernest Bloch Photographs </title>
    <updated>2011-08-19T16:21:13</updated>
    <summary>The Eric Johnson Collection of Ernest Bloch Photographs contains 105 black and white prints, the majority of which date from 1896-1937. Notable prints include "mushroom lady" (1912), trees depicting the characters of various composers, including Bach, Beethoven, and Debussy (1931 and 1935), and images of Alexandre Barjansky, Catherine Barjansky, Ada Clement, Lillian Hodgehead, Yehudi Menuhin, Roger Sessions, and Eug&#xE8;ne Ysa&#xFF;e. Photographs are arranged by date of inscription. "Research materials" contains preliminary and final drafts of Johnson's article, as well as a pamphlet on Bloch published by the Ernest Bloch Legacy Project in 2008.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu010003.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:10</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu010009.2</id>
    <title>Billy Byers Collection </title>
    <updated>2011-08-19T16:21:13</updated>
    <summary>This collection represents neither all nor most of Byers&#x2019; work as a composer, arranger and orchestrator, but provides a sampling of the diverse styles, musical forces, variety of performers and situations that he worked for and with. The scores here range from works for recordings, live performances, television shows, and film scores; for groups that range from small combos to big bands to orchestras of symphonic proportions; and for an eclectic array of singers, from pop to jazz to rock to rhythm and blues to disco; and even dancers. Missing here are any of Byers&#x2019; arrangements and orchestrations for Broadway musicals. It is hoped that someday this gap, too, will be filled by other collections in the Library.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu010009.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:11</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu010004.2</id>
    <title>Ira Gershwin Files from the Law Office of Leonard Saxe </title>
    <updated>2011-08-19T16:21:13</updated>
    <summary>The Ira Gershwin Files from the Law Office of Leonard Saxe spans the period 1948-1967. The collection includes contracts, correspondence, handwritten notes, financial documents, memos, pamphlets, programs, clippings, and other materials related to Saxe&#x2019;s legal representation of Ira Gershwin and his involvement with the Rose Gershwin Testamentary Trust.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu010004.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:10</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mbrsrs/eadmbrs.rs004003.2</id>
    <title> Papers from the Jim Walsh Collection </title>
    <updated>2011-08-19T16:21:12</updated>
    <summary>Jim Walsh devoted his life to collecting, researching, and writing about early popular recordings and recording artists. These papers make up part of the much larger Jim Walsh Collection of early recordings, audio equipment, and related items donated by Walsh to the Library of Congress between 1965 and 1987. The complete collection consists of approximately 40,000 discs, 500 cylinders, and 23 early phonographs. Recordings in the collection are primarily of popular and vernacular music recorded during the acoustical era (pre-1926). It includes a nearly complete run of 5,000 to 6,000 Edison "Diamond Disc" recordings as well as many early Edison cylinders.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmbrs.rs004003.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:07</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mbrsrs/eadmbrs.rs008002.2</id>
    <title>Photographs from the Mary Margaret McBride Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-08-19T16:21:12</updated>
    <summary>The photographs and accompanying paper documents form part of the much larger Mary Margaret McBride Collection, 1935-1950, in the Recorded Sound Section of the Motion Picture, Broadcasting and Recorded Sound Division, Library of Congress. Representing McBride's long and influential career as a pioneering woman radio journalist, the McBride Collection includes over twelve hundred hours of interview programs and other radio broadcasts. The photographs include portrait, publicity, and family photographs of Mary Margaret McBride; pictures of McBride and her guests, such as Omar Bradley, Mike Wallace, Eleanore Roosevelt, Thomas Dewey, and Mary Martin; shots of her radio program's anniversary celebrations; images relating to her 1960 autobiography, Out of the Air and of various products and locations; and depictions of broadcasting both in and outside of the studio.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmbrs.rs008002.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:07</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mbrsrs/eadmbrs.rs008001.2</id>
    <title>Jack Kapp Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-08-19T16:21:12</updated>
    <summary>Assembled by American Decca Records founder and president Jack Kapp, the collection consists of mostly original drawings by various magazine and newspaper cartoonists, such as Rube Goldberg, H. T. Webster, Gluyas Williams, L. M. Glackens, Burt Thomas, Fred Packer, Clifford Berryman, James Berryman, Jack Markow, and David Breger. The drawings, chiefly editorial cartoons, reflect the role of the phonograph in American life and offer historical commentary on the internal issues of the American phonograph industry, particularly the American Federation of Musicians recording ban of 1942-1944. The collection also features a framed album cover for the 1943 Decca Records cast recording of the musical, Oklahoma! The cast recording became a standard product category for record companies due to the immense success of this album.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmbrs.rs008001.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:08</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mbrsrs/eadmbrs.rs004002.2</id>
    <title>Carlton E. Morse Script Collection </title>
    <updated>2011-08-19T16:21:12</updated>
    <summary>When I Love a Mystery debuted in 1939, Carlton E. Morse was quite well known as the writer, director, and producer of the popular radio serial One Man's Family. One Man's Family became one of the longest-running American radio soap operas, broadcasting 3,256 episodes from 1932 to 1959. I Love a Mystery, which Morse also wrote, directed, and produced, aired until 1952. Morse created other radio serials including I Love Adventure, China Town Squad, Adventures by Morse, Family Skeleton, and His Honor, the Barber.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmbrs.rs004002.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:07</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mbrsrs/eadmbrs.rs004001.2</id>
    <title>Papers from the Isabelle Sayers Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-08-19T16:21:11</updated>
    <summary>These papers were part of the larger Isabelle Sayers Collection, a donation of early disc and wax cylinder recordings, phonographs, and related equipment donated to the Library of Congress in several increments between 1981 and 1987. The Sayers Collection includes some extremely rare items from the incunabula period (1884-1905) of the sound recording era. Among these rare items are 19th-century Berliner Gramophone Company discs, concert grand wax cylinders, and an assortment of playback equipment such as a "player-piano type harmonica." The collection totals approximately 2,000 wax cylinders, 4,000 discs, and 50 antique phonographs, as well as related equipment and assorted objects such as statues of the Victor dog, Edison banks, and old needle tins.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmbrs.rs004001.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:06</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mbrsrs/eadmbrs.rs005001.2</id>
    <title> Papers from the H. Vose Greenough Jr. Collection </title>
    <updated>2011-08-19T16:21:11</updated>
    <summary>The Papers from the H. Vose Greenough Jr. Collection is a small part of a larger gift of more than 700 acetate records and tapes Greenough recorded and left to the Library of Congress upon his death. The Greenough Collection includes materials from Technichord Records, a recording company he founded located in Brookline, Massachusetts, as well as his personal papers.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmbrs.rs005001.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:06</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mbrsrs/eadmbrs.rs006002.2</id>
    <title>Transcripts and Photographs from the John Peter Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-08-19T16:21:11</updated>
    <summary>Consists of interview transcripts and photographs used by John Peter in his books on 20th-century architects. Architects who are particularly well represented in these materials include Buckminster Fuller, Walter Gropius, Philip Johnson, Louis Kahn, Le Corbusier, Ludwig Mies van der Rohe, Richard Neutra, I.M. Pei, Eero Saarinen, Minoru Yamasaki, and Frank Lloyd Wright.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmbrs.rs006002.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:07</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mbrsrs/eadmbrs.rs006001.2</id>
    <title>Papers from the John Secrist Jr. Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-08-19T16:21:11</updated>
    <summary>These papers comprise a small part of the major collection of nearly 1,700 operatic recordings acquired by John Secrist. Strengths of the recorded sound collection include large runs of Enrico Caruso and Rosa Ponselle recordings; the collection is further distinguished by being in near-mint condition due to Secrist's exacting standards. The papers explain and index the Secrist recordings, while discographic and photographic materials provide information on the artists whose work he collected.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmbrs.rs006001.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:06</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu007001.2</id>
    <title>Edward Beach Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-08-19T16:21:10</updated>
    <summary>The Edward Beach Collection consists exclusively of photographs and other iconography of musicians. Primarily, the images are of jazz musicians; also represented are a few notable figures from other musical and artistic disciplines. The bulk of the material dates from the 1950s through the mid-1970s; one photograph is dated 1940.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu007001.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:03</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu010012.2</id>
    <title>Mario Castelnuovo-Tedesco Papers </title>
    <updated>2011-08-19T16:21:10</updated>
    <summary> The Mario Castelnuovo-Tedesco Papers span the period 1822-1998, with the majority of the materials dating from 1920-1968. The collection includes holograph and copyist music manuscripts, printed music, libretti, writings, personal and family correspondence, business files, photographs, programs, reviews, biographical materials, film music materials, and an assortment of books owned by the composer.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu010012.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:04</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu009014.2</id>
    <title>Susannah Armstrong Coleman Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-08-19T16:21:10</updated>
    <summary>The Susannah Armstrong Coleman Collection spans the period 1912-1953; the bulk of the materials date from 1930-1949. The collection includes music manuscripts, organizational publications, correspondence, programs, photographs, biographical notes, clippings, and miscellaneous items. Correspondence principally consists of greeting cards from Mrs. Coleman's friends and acquaintances. The clippings focus on collegiate programs and the activities of her instructors at the Northwestern University School of Music. Pamphlets and publications of Mu Phi Epsilon and Pi Kappa Lambda portray Coleman as an invested member who actively contributed to organizational events.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu009014.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:04</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu010021.2</id>
    <title>Harriet Winslow Collection of Nadia Boulanger Materials </title>
    <updated>2011-08-19T16:21:09</updated>
    <summary>The Harriet Winslow Collection of Nadia Boulanger Materials spans the period 1956 to 1964 and consists of photographs, concert programs, and clippings related to the influential French composer, conductor, and teacher. All photographs are inscribed with notes or short greetings that identify the depicted individuals and places. Most portray Boulanger alone or with others, in her apartment, at the Conservatoire am&#xE9;ricain de Fontainebleau, or while traveling. The majority of the programs are from the Conservatoire am&#xE9;ricain de Fontainebleau and document performances by faculty members, students, and visiting ensembles. The remaining programs are from Boulanger's visits to the United States in 1958 and 1962 and from her visits to other countries between these dates. These special appearances, usually as conductor, performer, or teacher, are covered in greater detail in the clippings file. Also included is a record review by Marc Blitzstein about compositions by Lili Boulanger, sister of Nadia, who died at the age of twenty-four.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu010021.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:02</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu010023.2</id>
    <title>Ella Fitzgerald Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-08-19T16:21:09</updated>
    <summary>Known as the &#x201C;First Lady of Song,&#x201D; Ella Fitzgerald sang professionally over a career that spanned some fifty-seven years. More than 2,300 recordings are known to exist of over 1,000 songs; Fitzgerald is thought to be more recorded than any other singer. Her repertoire included works from various genres, including musical theater, rhythm and blues, rock and roll, religious works, and Latin-American songs. Under the guidance of manager and producer, Norman Granz, Fitzgerald recorded several &#x201C;songbooks&#x201D; of the works of individual composers and lyricists.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu010023.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-10-13T15:16:01</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu010028.2</id>
    <title>Morton Gould Papers </title>
    <updated>2011-08-19T16:21:09</updated>
    <summary>Music materials from the Morton Gould Papers span the period 1920 to 1995, with the majority dating from 1937 to 1995. The materials principally consist of holograph or copyist manuscripts, printed scores, orchestral parts, lyric sheets, and sketches of Gould's compositions and arrangements. Many of the scores, especially the photo-reproduced manuscripts, contain pencil annotations, chiefly in the hand of the composer, that indicate corrections, or, for those works conducted by Gould, performance adjustments. Works are arranged categorically by instrumentation and alphabetically by title therein. Entries indicate specific instrumentation, date of composition (if known), and commissioning organization (if applicable).</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu010028.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-12-20T20:06:55</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu003011.2</id>
    <title>Serge Diaghilev/Serge Lifar Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-08-19T16:21:08</updated>
    <summary>He was neither a painter, nor a dancer, nor had extensive musical training, yet by means of his great organizational and managerial skills, as well as by a keen aesthetic sense and an unerring sense of style, Serge Diaghilev had a profound influence on the course of music, ballet and art in the twentieth century.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu003011.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:01</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu009010.2</id>
    <title>Robert Di Domenica Collection </title>
    <updated>2011-08-19T16:21:07</updated>
    <summary>Robert Di Domenica has had a notable career as a flutist, composer, and music educator. The collection reflects all three of these activities. However, the majority of the material relates to his endeavors as a composer. The collection includes the manuscripts of compositions from his student days through his mature works. Mr. Di Domenica is still composing, and the library hopes to receive future manuscripts.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu009010.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:01</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu007003.2</id>
    <title>Mannes - Damrosch Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-08-19T16:21:07</updated>
    <summary>The Mannes-Damrosch Collection comprises correspondence and other materials from the Mannes family&#x2014;David and Clara Damrosch Mannes and their children Leopold and Marya Mannes&#x2014;and members of the Damrosch family including Leopold Damrosch and his sons, Frank and Walter Damrosch. The collection spans 1848-1986, with the majority of the materials dating from 1900-1950. It includes biographical materials, correspondence, writings, music, programs, clippings, artwork, photographs, awards, and other materials.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu007003.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:01</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu007002.2</id>
    <title>Damrosch - Tee Van Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-08-19T16:21:07</updated>
    <summary>The Damrosch-Tee Van Collection consists of the papers of Frank and Leopold Damrosch and their families. The date span of the collection is 1856-1969, with the bulk of the materials dating from the 1870s to the 1930s. The collection includes biographical materials, correspondence, writings, manuscript and printed music, financial and legal papers, programs, scrapbooks, artwork, and photographs.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu007002.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:00</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu010031.2</id>
    <title>Charlie Barnet Collection of Big Band Arrangements</title>
    <updated>2011-08-19T16:21:06</updated>
    <summary>The Charlie Barnet Collection of Big Band Arrangements is made up entirely of arrangements for approximately 650 songs and instrumental numbers used by Barnet and his band. The majority of these arrangements are represented by full scores, though thirty-seven are represented by parts only, and an additional thirty-one include both a full score and parts. Unless otherwise noted, everything listed is a full score. In a few instances, a score seems to fall somewhere between what would be identified as a full score and a short score (a score that combines, for instance, instrumental parts on one stave, and often includes no piano or rhythm part). Some songs are represented by more than one arrangement. There are twenty-two arrangements for medleys.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu010031.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-12-20T20:06:54</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu005002.2</id>
    <title>Joint Army and Navy Committee on Welfare and Recreation, Sub-Committee on Music Papers</title>
    <updated>2011-08-19T16:21:05</updated>
    <summary>On September 25, 1941, the Joint Army and Navy Committee on Welfare and Recreation announced the appointment of a Sub-committee on Music, formed to advise the Army, Navy and Marine Corps on all matters pertaining to musical activities within military camps and reservations during and after World War II (1941 to 1946). The Sub-committee was also to aid in coordinating plans for musical entertainment of the soldiers in the communities outside the camps and stations. Dr. Harold Spivacke, chief of the Music Division at the Library of Congress from 1937 to 1972, was named as the chairman. This collection consists of the working papers of the Sub-committee.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu005002.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:55</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu005004.2</id>
    <title>Vernon Duke Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-08-19T16:21:04</updated>
    <summary>In addition to being a renowned composer, Vernon Duke was an author, poet, translator, gourmand, businessman, bon vivant, and an intellectual. Duke's eclecticisim is well documented in the Vernon Duke Collection. As a result, the collection is rich in research potential for a wide variety of topics. The music holographs cover the entire length of Vernon Duke's career--from compositions dating from his student days in 1918 (Morceaux pour piano, op. 1, composed when he was fifteen) to works from 1968 (the revised version of his ballet Entr'acte)--a year before he died. The collection represents the dual nature of Dukelsky/Duke as a composer of twentieth century European/Russian influenced "serious" or "classical" music, and a composer of jazz-influenced American popular and show music. Documenting his position as an international professional in the world of music, the collection contains voluminous correspondence between Duke and prominent composers, conductors, scholars, producers, lyricists, journals, universities and performers.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu005004.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:54</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/eadafc.af011014.2</id>
    <title>1987 Neptune Plaza Concert Series Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-08-19T16:21:04</updated>
    <summary>The 1987 Neptune Plaza Concert Series Collection consists of manuscript and print materials, audio recordings, and graphic materials that document the 1987 concert series sponsored by the American Folklife Center. The annual series, which began in 1977, features the presentation of folk traditions from many cultures. The concerts take place on the Neptune Plaza at the front of the Jefferson Building of the Library of Congress between April and September. Adverse weather conditions sometimes force the concerts indoors. The 1987 series was produced with the assistance of the National Council for the Traditional Arts.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadafc.af011014.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-08-19T16:21:04</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/eadafc.af011012.2</id>
    <title> 1985 Neptune Plaza Concert Series Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-08-19T16:21:03</updated>
    <summary>The 1985 Neptune Plaza Concert Series Collection consists of manuscript and print materials, audio recordings, and graphic materials that document the 1985 concert series sponsored by the American Folklife Center. The annual series, which began in 1977, features the presentation of folk traditions from many cultures. The concerts take place on the Neptune Plaza at the front of the Jefferson Building of the Library of Congress between May and September. Adverse weather conditions sometimes force the concerts indoors. The 1985 series was produced with the assistance of the National Council for the Traditional Arts. </summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadafc.af011012.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-08-19T16:21:03</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mbrsrs/eadmbrs.rs004004.2</id>
    <title>Manfred F. DeMartino Collection of CBS Radio Scripts </title>
    <updated>2011-08-19T16:21:03</updated>
    <summary>The collection consists of scripts and a photograph acquired by Manfred Frank DeMartino while working backstage at CBS radio during the mid-1940s. Includes scripts for the Frank Sinatra Show, Philip Morris Playhouse, and Your Hit Parade, many of which are autographed by performers. The scripts include advertisements for sponsors such as Vimms Vitamins, Philip Morris cigarettes, and the American Tobacco Company's Lucky Strike cigarettes. The black and white photograph of Philip Morris spokesman Johnny Roventini is autographed.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmbrs.rs004004.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:50</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/eadafc.af011010.2</id>
    <title> 1983 Neptune Plaza Concert Series Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-08-19T16:21:03</updated>
    <summary>The 1983 Neptune Plaza Concert Series Collection consists of manuscript and print materials, audio recordings, and graphic materials that document the 1983 concert series sponsored by the American Folklife Center. The annual series, which began in 1977, features the presentation of folk traditions from many cultures. The concerts take place on the Neptune Plaza at the front of the Jefferson Building of the Library of Congress between May and September. Adverse weather conditions sometimes force the concerts indoors. The 1983 series was produced with the assistance of the National Council for the Traditional Arts.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadafc.af011010.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-07-14T16:54:56</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/eadafc.af011013.2</id>
    <title>1986 Neptune Plaza Concert Series Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-08-19T16:21:03</updated>
    <summary>The 1986 Neptune Plaza Concert Series Collection consists of manuscript and print materials, audio recordings, and graphic materials that document the 1986 concert series sponsored by the American Folklife Center. The annual series, which began in 1977, features the presentation of folk traditions from many cultures. The concerts take place on the Neptune Plaza at the front of the Jefferson Building of the Library of Congress between May and September. Adverse weather conditions sometimes force the concerts indoors. The 1986 series was produced with the assistance of the National Council for the Traditional Arts. </summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadafc.af011013.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-08-19T16:21:03</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/eadafc.af011011.2</id>
    <title> 1984 Neptune Plaza Concert Series Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-08-19T16:21:03</updated>
    <summary>The 1984 Neptune Plaza Concert Series Collection consists of manuscript and print materials, audio recordings, and graphic materials that document the 1984 concert series sponsored by the American Folklife Center. The annual series, which began in 1977, features the presentation of folk traditions from many cultures. The 1984 series was produced with the assistance of the National Council for the Traditional Arts. </summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadafc.af011011.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-07-14T16:54:56</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu006001.2</id>
    <title>Franziska Boas Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-08-19T16:21:01</updated>
    <summary>The Franziska Boas collection is an extensive collection of multi-format materials documenting the professional and personal life of Franziska Boas. The collection spans Boas' career, from her academic training at Barnard College through her professional work as a dance teacher, accompanist, therapist and ethnologist, and includes documentation of her work as a social activist and as a community educator after her retirement.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu006001.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:42</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu006002.2</id>
    <title>Bob Fosse and Gwen Verdon Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-08-19T16:21:00</updated>
    <summary>The Bob Fosse and Gwen Verdon Collection is an extensive collection of multi-format materials documenting the professional lives of two of America's most notable artists of the twentieth century. The collection spans both careers from their early appearances and projects through Fosse's last work.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu006002.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:41</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu006004.2</id>
    <title>Alexandra Danilova Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-08-19T16:20:59</updated>
    <summary>The Alexandra Danilova Collection consists of correspondence, programs, newspaper clippings and magazine articles, manuscripts and typescripts relating to speeches and lectures given by Danilova, writings of Danilova and others, typescripts of her memoirs, photographs, awards and honors, books, art catalogs, video- and audiocassettes, music, artwork, miscellaneous papers, and other material are all within its scope. The collection also contains dance-related writings--several typescripts and numerous books--by various other people, as well as miscellaneous printed material, personal papers, and memorabilia. The vast majority of the non-photographic material originates from the period in Danilova&#x2019;s life after she had retired from performing, when she had settled into a life of teaching at the School of American Ballet. The thirteen major groupings, or "series," included herein are roughly ordered from most important or complete--photographs, correspondence, writings, programs, and press--to least important or complete--music, artwork, and personal materials. Audiovisual materials are listed last; they are housed in the Motion Picture, Broadcasting, and Recorded Sound Division. The following are brief descriptions of the scope and content of each series.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu006004.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:40</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu003005.2</id>
    <title>Jacobo Ficher Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-08-19T16:20:59</updated>
    <summary>The Jacobo Ficher Collection reveals a composer who was significantly associated with the Argentinean music of the twentieth century. In addition to being a major creator, he developed a brilliant career as an orchestra conductor, prominent teacher and violinist.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu003005.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:38</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu003003.2</id>
    <title>Lauro Ayestar&#xE1;n Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-08-19T16:20:57</updated>
    <summary>The Lauro Ayestar&#xE1;n Collection reveals the life-time dedication of a distinguished musicologist and avid researcher who collected the core of the Uruguayan music plus music of foreign origin performed in Uruguay, in both holograph and scores through a systematic, tireless and continuous search throughout Uruguay, including the Montevideo's flea market and dusty-old-used-book stores. He also must be remembered as a dedicated teacher with a profound understanding of pedagogy and a vast knowledge of the western hemisphere history of music, and the mind of a scholar interested in any topic related to culture. In addition of publishing a considerable number of books he collaborated as contributor to many dictionaries, encyclopedias and musical and folkloric books. A third aspect of his personality encompasses the systematic recollection of the Uruguayan folklore in situ, with a total of 4.000 wire-recordings, hold actually in the Musicological Section of the Museum of National History in Montevideo.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu003003.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:36</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu003007.2</id>
    <title>Dallapiccola/Dwight Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-08-19T16:20:56</updated>
    <summary>The bulk of this collection represents Dallapiccola's correspondence with Margaret (Peggie) Dwight during the years of their association, from 1951 to 1975. This correspondence includes over 300 letters (written mostly in French), as well as various postcards and telegrams. In addition, there are over two hundred articles and programs relating to Dallapiccola's career, mostly collected during those years.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu003007.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:32</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu003009.2</id>
    <title>Ernest Bloch Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-08-19T16:20:56</updated>
    <summary>The Bloch Collection covers the life and careers of the Jewish Swiss-born violinist/composer/conductor and photographer, beginning with his grade school report cards, dated 1888 through 1894, and continuing beyond his death in 1959 with the publication of some musical works, and exhibitions of his photography. Music having been the primary focus of his life, Bloch's photographic skills are lesser known. Oregonians are more familiar with this aspect of his life owing to several exhibitions of his output by the Center for Creative Photography in Portland. The Collection includes manuscripts (music and lecture material), correspondence, business papers, photographs, programs, promotional material, writings about Ernest Bloch, personal papers, printed matter, and the material donated by Carolyn Epes.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu003009.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:33</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu001001.2</id>
    <title>Irving Fine Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-08-19T16:20:55</updated>
    <summary>The bulk of the materials in the collection are musical scores and sketches representing virtually the entire musical output of the composer. Among these materials are manuscripts for Alice in Wonderland (1942); The Hour Glass (1949), a song cycle for unaccompanied chorus set to texts by Ben Jonson; Mutability, a song cycle for contralto and piano originally commissioned by the Creative Concerts Guild, Inc., in 1952; Serious Song (1955), for string orchestra; and Symphony 1962, which was performed by the Boston Symphony Orchestra shortly before Fine's death in 1962.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu001001.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:31</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.pnp/eadpnp.pp002002.2</id>
    <title>Tobacco label collection (Library of Congress)</title>
    <updated>2011-08-19T16:20:52</updated>
    <summary>Images reflect varied aspects of American history, popular culture, and politics of the nineteenth century. Examples of topics depicted include African-Americans, animals, children, Civil War generals, events, flags, gods&amp;goddesses, humorous situations, Indians, literary characters, people, smoking, portraits of American and European political figures, sports, symbols, the theater and theatrical personalities, the tobacco industry, and women.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadpnp.pp002002.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:25</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu011006.2</id>
    <title>Merle Montgomery Papers </title>
    <updated>2011-07-14T16:54:59</updated>
    <summary>The papers of Merle Montgomery (1904-1986) span the years 1904-1983, with the bulk of the material dating from 1960 to 1980. The papers highlight Montgomery's career and leadership roles in several organizations, programs, and projects in support of music, education and the arts. The collection chronicles her presidencies with the National Federation of Music Clubs from 1971-1975 and the National Music Council from 1975-1979, her career with music publishing firm Carl Fischer Inc., from the mid-1940s to 1971, her management of the Bicentennial Parade of American Music, her scholarly work on the Scribner Music Library, from around 1961 to 1972, and more. There is a small amount of personal material, including correspondence with family and friends, photographs, and biographical documents and clippings. The papers are organized into the following series: Correspondence, Biographical Materials, Business Papers, Photographs, Promotional Materials, Programs, Clippings, Publications, and Miscellany.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu011006.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-07-14T16:54:59</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu011008.2</id>
    <title>Louis Kaufman Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-07-14T16:54:58</updated>
    <summary>Materials from the Louis Kaufman Collection span the period 1925 to 2008. The bulk of the collection contains correspondence to Louis and Annette Kaufman from prominent musical and artistic figures of the 20th century, including Milton Avery, Samuel Barber, Robert Russell Bennett, David Burliuk, Mario Castelnuovo-Tedesco, Carlos Ch&#xE1;vez, Aaron Copland, David Diamond, Olin Downes, Vernon Duke (Vladimir Dukelsky), Albert Einstein, Gerald Finzi, Morton Gould, Jonathan Griffin, Bernard Herrmann, Erich Wolfgang Korngold, Nikolai Lopatnikoff, Gian Francesco Malipiero, Bohuslav Martin&#x16F;, Darius Milhaud, Dimitri Mitropoulos, Walter Piston, Quincy Porter, Francis Poulenc, George Rochberg, Mikl&#xF3;s R&#xF3;zsa, Henri Sauguet, William Grant Still, Ernst Toch, Alice B. Toklas, and Ralph Vaughan Williams. The correspondence also reflects the Kaufmans&#x2019; involvement with art collecting and lending to various art galleries and museums, as well as their philanthropic activities with important artists. </summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu011008.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-07-14T16:54:58</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu011007.2</id>
    <title>J. Fischer&amp;Bro. Music Publishers Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-07-14T16:54:58</updated>
    <summary>The J. Fischer&amp;Bro. Music Publishers Collection consists of autograph manuscripts of music used for publishing purposes and dating from 1950 to 1970. The majority of the manuscripts are choral works, both sacred and secular, many with piano or organ accompaniment. In addition, original works for organ and piano are included, as well as piano and organ transcriptions. Most of these works were published by Fischer&amp;Bro. music publishers.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu011007.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-07-14T16:54:58</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu002010.2</id>
    <title>Samuel P. Warren Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-07-14T16:54:55</updated>
    <summary>The Samuel P. Warren Collection consists of correspondence, concert and recital programs, church service programs and related materials that were either collected by Warren himself or given to him by his students, colleagues and others in the New York City and throughout the United States. The collection spans the years from 1850 to 1914, with the bulk of the material covering the years 1880-1910.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu002010.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:23</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.gmd/eadgmd.gm001001.2</id>
    <title>Oregon Department of Transportation City Maps</title>
    <updated>2011-06-21T11:34:53</updated>
    <summary>This finding aid lists maps of incorporated towns issued by the Oregon Department of Transporation and held in the Geography&amp;Map Division. The dates within the list represent the holdings of the Division. These city maps show highways, streets, parks, railroads, schools, public buildings, section corners, water features, land features, and various boundaries. The list is arranged alphabetically by city name.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadgmd.gm001001.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:20</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu009007.2</id>
    <title>Joe Haymes Big Band Arrangements </title>
    <updated>2011-06-21T11:34:47</updated>
    <summary>The collection chiefly consists of Joe Haymes' musical arrangements, including many of his own compositions. Unless otherwise noted, the music manuscripts are in Haymes&#x2019; own hand, and include scores, parts, lead sheets, piano-vocal scores, and sketches. Miscellaneous items in the collection include several photographs, clippings, correspondence, and a discography. </summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu009007.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:09</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu009016.2</id>
    <title>Charles Hambitzer Music Manuscripts </title>
    <updated>2011-06-21T11:34:46</updated>
    <summary>The Charles Hambitzer manuscripts consist of sixteen orchestral scores or part sets for tone poems and incidental music, as well as several short pieces for various instruments and approximately twenty-five songs and stage numbers in piano-vocal format. Sketches and miscellaneous fragments are also represented. Although George Gershwin once recalled that Hambitzer, his first significant music teacher, &#x201C;wrote what I then considered the finest light music,&#x201D; there appears to be no connection between these manuscripts and Gershwin&#x2019;s own compositions.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu009016.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:03</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu010013.2</id>
    <title>Harriet Hoctor Collection </title>
    <updated>2011-06-21T11:34:44</updated>
    <summary>The Harriet Hoctor Collection is comprised of materials that document her professional life as a vaudeville, Broadway, and film dancer. The collection contains materials that span her early dance training at the Louis H. Chalif Normal School of Dancing in New York in 1917 to the founding of the Harriet Hoctor Ballet School in Boston in 1945.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu010013.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:00</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/eadafc.af006006.2</id>
    <title> Four Masters of Chinese Storytelling Video Collection </title>
    <updated>2011-06-21T11:34:42</updated>
    <summary>This collection is the product of the "Large-scale Registration of Chinese Storytelling" conducted by Dr. Vibeke B&#xF8;rdahl and Fei Li between 2001 and 2003. During this project, the repertories of four masters of Chinese storytelling in Yangzhou - Dai Buzhang, Fei Zhengliang (Fei Li), Gao Zaihua, and Ren Jitang (Ren Dekun) - were filmed on video for a total of 360 hours of storytelling. The videotapes were then converted into sets of video compact discs (VCDs) and donated to research institutions in Asia, Europe, and the United States.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadafc.af006006.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:56</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/eadmus.mu003008.2</id>
    <title>Jascha Heifetz Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-06-21T11:34:36</updated>
    <summary>The Jascha Heifetz Collection, in the breadth and variety of its contents, gives a rare and comprehensive look at the life of one of history's most important violinists. Heifetz's personal music library includes his original compositions, arrangements and transcriptions (some of which are unpublished), his annotated parts and scores, holographs and manuscripts of many of his contemporaries, and hundreds of printed scores (at least some of which appear to have been previously owned by Joseph Achron). Concert programs document his performances from 1911 to 1974, and photographs, photo albums, and scrapbooks, encompassing the violinist's entire life, capture Heifetz in performance, with his family, and with notable personalities. And the correspondence, constituting a small part of the collection, contains letters from such important musical figures of the twentieth-century as Leopold Auer, Benjamin Britten, Sergei Prokofiev, George Bernard Shaw, and Sir William Walton.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmus.mu003008.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:33</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/eadafc.af011009.2</id>
    <title> 1982 Neptune Plaza Concert Series Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-05-23T14:32:20</updated>
    <summary>The 1982 Neptune Plaza Concert Series Collection consists of manuscript and print materials, audio recordings, and graphic materials that document the 1982 concert series sponsored by the American Folklife Center. The annual series, which began in 1977, features the presentation of folk traditions from many cultures. The concerts take place on the Neptune Plaza at the front of the Jefferson Building of the Library of Congress between May and October. Adverse weather conditions sometimes force the concerts indoors. The 1982 series was produced with the assistance of the National Council for the Traditional Arts.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadafc.af011009.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-05-23T14:32:20</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/eadafc.af011001.2</id>
    <title> 1978 Neptune Plaza Concert Series Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-05-23T14:32:19</updated>
    <summary>The 1978 Neptune Plaza Concert Series Collection consists of manuscript and print materials, audio recordings, and graphic materials that document the 1978 concert series sponsored by the American Folklife Center. The annual series, which began in 1977, features the presentation of folk traditions from many cultures. The concerts took place on the Neptune Plaza at the front of the Jefferson Building of the Library of Congress between April and September. Adverse weather conditions sometimes forced the concerts indoors. The 1978 series was produced with the assistance of the National Council for the Traditional Arts.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadafc.af011001.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-03-25T13:30:38</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mbrsmi/eadmbrsmi.mi007001.2</id>
    <title>Fox Movietone Newsreel Collection - World War II Paper Records</title>
    <updated>2011-04-26T15:02:24</updated>
    <summary>Although the title of this portion of the Fox Movietone newsreel collection designates World War II records, it is noted that other stories are reported, including sports, fashion, news of the nation, weather disasters, and entertainment. While the war dominated the news reported during this period, the news on the American home front is also well documented in this collection. The finding aid created in 2007 describes the materials in the Fox Movietone newsreel collection documenting the US involvement in World War II, roughly 1941-1946. The entire collection includes materials from 1916-1963. It is anticipated that the remainder of the materials will be processed and added to this finding aid in the future. </summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadmbrsmi.mi007001.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:06</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.pnp/eadpnp.pp004001.2</id>
    <title>Exit Art "Reactions" exhibit collection</title>
    <updated>2011-04-26T15:02:20</updated>
    <summary>Pictures and manuscripts (collages, digital prints, drawings, paintings, photographs, poetry, letters, etc.) by professional artists, non-artists, and children reflecting personal responses to the terrorist attacks of September 11th, 2001.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadpnp.pp004001.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:39</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/eadafc.af010004.2</id>
    <title>World War II Rumor Project Collection</title>
    <updated>2011-03-04T15:34:43</updated>
    <summary>The World War II Rumor Project Collection contains manuscript materials compiled by the Office of War Information (OWI). The OWI was established by an Executive order on June 13, 1942, for the purpose of achieving a coordinated governmental war information program. The information program was designed to promote an informed and intelligent understanding of the status and progress of the war effort, war policies, activities, and aims of the United States government. All functions of the Office of Facts and Figures and of the Office of Government Reports, and parts of the functions and related records of two other agencies were transferred to the OWI. </summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadafc.af010004.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2011-03-04T15:34:43</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.pnp/eadpnp.pp002004.2</id>
    <title>Film stills of productions featuring actress May Robson</title>
    <updated>2011-01-28T18:14:50</updated>
    <summary>LOT includes over 40 film titles. Images depict Robson and other actors in scenes from the films; Robson with co-stars in a few off-camera shots. Also includes group portraits of cast members and single portraits of Robson in costume.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadpnp.pp002004.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:14</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.pnp/eadpnp.pp002006.2</id>
    <title>Exhibition photographs depicting prominent men in art, law, politics, and government</title>
    <updated>2010-11-22T18:26:29</updated>
    <summary>Formal portraits of national and international figures. Diplomats, statesmen, and political figures are featured prominently throughout the LOT. Includes some portraits of U.S. Supreme Court justices, architects, and artists. Also one portrait of Alice Acheson.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadpnp.pp002006.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:23</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.pnp/eadpnp.pp002010.2</id>
    <title>Visual materials from the Booker T. Washington papers</title>
    <updated>2010-11-22T18:26:28</updated>
    <summary>Photographs document the activities of Booker T. Washington as a leader and agrarian organizer in the South at the turn of the century. Many depict Booker T. Washington's speaking engagements at such places as Ocala, Tallahasee, and Daytona, Fla.; Mound Bayou, Miss.; and Baton Rouge, La. The collection also includes photographs that document classes and activities at the Tuskegee Normal and Industrial Institute, Tuskegee, Ala., including a parade for the celebration of the visit of President Theodore Roosevelt on October 24, 1905; celebrations for the twenty-fifth anniversary of the Institute in 1906; and students building dormitories and other facilities. Also includes a group portrait of the faculty of the Institute in 1897, as well as a few images of such faculty members as Frederick Douglass, Emmett Scott, and George Washington Carver. In addition, the collection contains portraits of other African Americans, including Blanche K. Bruce, Henry O. Tanner, John R. Lynch, Richard T. Greener, and John M. Langston, as well as alumni of Tuskegee Institute. Also includes portraits of African American students at other schools in the South. Many images are unique because of personal inscriptions to Booker T. Washington.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadpnp.pp002010.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:23</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.pnp/eadpnp.pp002005.2</id>
    <title>Portraits of prominent men in art, law, politics, and government</title>
    <updated>2010-11-22T18:26:28</updated>
    <summary>Formal portraits of national and international figures. Diplomats, statesmen, and political figures are featured prominently throughout the LOT. Includes some portraits of U.S. Supreme Court justices, architects, and artists. Also one portrait of Alice Acheson and one of Mary Rockefeller (Mrs. Nelson Rockefeller).</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadpnp.pp002005.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:23</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/eadafc.af008001.2</id>
    <title> Sara L. M. Davis Collection on Tai L&#xFC;e Culture</title>
    <updated>2010-11-22T18:26:15</updated>
    <summary>This ethnographic collection is based on the original field work that anthropologist Sara L. M. Davis conducted in Sipsongpanna (Xishuangbanna in Chinese), Yunnan Province, China, and in Kengtung, Shang State, Burma [Myanmar], between 1997 and 2003. The multi-format materials in this collection document Tai L&#xFC;e religious rituals, epic oral narratives, popular songs and performances for tourists, as well as interviews with oral poets and popular singers. They consist of her field notes, audio and video recordings, graphic images in the form of photographs and slides, and books published in Yunnan. This research formed the basis of Davis&#x2019;s book, Song and Silence: Ethnic Revival on China's Southwest Borders (Columbia University Press, 2005). Davis originally traveled to China's southwest borders to conduct doctoral research on ethnic minority folklore, focusing primarily on oral narrative poetry, known as Tai L&#xFC;e changkhap or skilled chants. (As used by Davis, changkhap may refer to the genre or to the performers or singers of changkhap.) She was based in the subtropical area of Sipsongpanna in the southwestern region of China, bordering Burma and Laos. Davis lived in Jinghong, the capital of this region, from 1997 to 1998 and made subsequent visits to the area through 2003. </summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadafc.af008001.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:59:08</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/eadafc.af005002.2</id>
    <title>September 11, 2001 Documentary Project Collection</title>
    <updated>2010-11-22T18:26:03</updated>
    <summary>On September 12, 2001, the American Folklife Center at the Library of Congress sent a notice to folklorists and ethnographers across the nation asking them to record on audiotape the thoughts and feelings expressed by individuals and communities following the terrorist attacks of September 11, 2001. The project was developed by Ann Hoog, who collaborated with American Folklife Center Director Peggy Bulger in the original call for participation. Materials were mailed to the Library of Congress beginning in September 2001. The collection reflects the regional, ethnic, socioeconomic, and political diversity of Americans at the time of the September 11 attacks.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadafc.af005002.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:56</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/eadafc.af006009.2</id>
    <title> Sergei Zhirkevich Photograph Collection </title>
    <updated>2010-11-22T18:26:03</updated>
    <summary>The photographic prints and manuscript material were produced during an ethnographic study conducted by Sergei Zhirkevich in which he documented the enduring folk and religious traditions of regional provincial life in the former Soviet Union. Zhirkevich spent over a decade interviewing local people, recording music, and photographing in the Pskov Region of Russia, the former Baltic states, the Leningrad region, Kazakhstan, and the region north of the Caucasus Mountains. The resulting monograph, Ot Zamogil'ia do Blagodati (From Beyond the Grave to Blessed Grace), was published in 1999.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadafc.af006009.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:56</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/eadafc.af007005.2</id>
    <title> Ray M. Lawless Collection </title>
    <updated>2010-11-22T18:26:00</updated>
    <summary>Between 1952 and 1959, Lawless wrote to approximately two hundred "folksingers" and "singers of folksongs," requesting information about their lives and careers in preparation for his book Folksingers and Folksongs in America. Lawless contacted both professional and non-professional singers and also wrote to several collectors of folksongs and collectors of folk instruments. The bulk of the collection consists of Lawless's correspondence with the singers, completed questionnaires, and information sent by the singers to Lawless. Most singers also sent one or more photographs.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadafc.af007005.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:53</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.gmd/eadgmd.gm007001.2</id>
    <title>Herold J. Wiens Collection</title>
    <updated>2010-11-22T18:25:58</updated>
    <summary>The Herold J. Wiens Collection consists of pen and ink drawings, pencil sketches, facsimiles, and photographs of aerial views showing all or part of China during the period of World War II. The collection also consists of technical drawing equipment, notes, charts, atlases, some books, personal folders, letters, correspondence, and other miscellaneous items. Covers China, Marshall Islands (1951-1952), and parts of Asia. On pilot maps shows graphic flight line index.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadgmd.gm007001.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:49</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/eadafc.af006008.2</id>
    <title> Ken Lindsay Collection of Woody Guthrie Correspondence </title>
    <updated>2010-11-22T18:25:58</updated>
    <summary>The correspondence between Ken Lindsay and Woody Guthrie began in 1952, while Lindsay was responsible for the mail order record department at the International Bookshop on Charing Cross Road in London, England. Lindsay first wrote to Guthrie encouraging him to write and record material for the European market. Although the recording projects and the European tours discussed in their letters never materialized, this correspondence (1952-1953) captures the development of a special relationship between two men who never met, but shared a passion for music. The correspondence also provides a glimpse at the creative flair and the personal challenges that shaped this period of Guthrie&#x2019;s life.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadafc.af006008.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:50</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/eadafc.af998001.2</id>
    <title>Duncan Emrich Autograph Album Collection</title>
    <updated>2010-11-22T18:25:54</updated>
    <summary>The collection consists of twenty autograph albums and ephemera from the states of Iowa, Illinois, Indiana, Michigan, Missouri, and New York dating from 1843 through 1923, collected by Duncan Emrich, head of the Archive of Folk Song, 1945-1956. Emrich's collection is comprised of eight albums from the Habel, Steinmetz, Hale, and Wehls families, donated by Mrs. Orville B. Craig of Independence, Iowa, in 1955; three albums apparently donated by Neva Ruth Dye of Independence, Iowa, in 1956; plus seven albums, one set of loose pages from an album, and one greeting card, donated by various individuals. </summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadafc.af998001.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:45</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.pnp/eadpnp.pp002001.2</id>
    <title>Music cover collection (Library of Congress)</title>
    <updated>2010-11-22T18:25:38</updated>
    <summary>Images reflect varied aspects of American history, culture, and politics of the nineteenth century. Examples of topics depicted include African Americans; animals; children; cities; the Civil War; daily life; dancing; educational institutions; emblems and symbols; entertainers; fashion; flags; genre scenes; landscapes; love and marriage; military personnel; musical instruments and people playing instruments; U.S. Presidents; sports; theater; transportation; and women.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadpnp.pp002001.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:24</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.pnp/eadpnp.pp002003.2</id>
    <title>Patent medicine labels and advertisements (Library of Congress)</title>
    <updated>2010-11-22T18:25:38</updated>
    <summary>Examples of topics depicted include American Indians, animals, children, flowers, medicinal plants, mythological characters, people taking or administering medications, sick and cured people, symbols, and women. Also includes genre prints, portraits of product promoters or developers.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadpnp.pp002003.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:25</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/eadafc.af001001.2</id>
    <title> Woody Guthrie Manuscript Collection </title>
    <updated>2010-11-22T18:25:30</updated>
    <summary>Woody Guthrie was a prolific artist known for his achievements as a singer-songwriter and as an author. Guthrie toured and performed for a period of approximately twenty-five years, exhibiting a life-long dedication to social activism by playing his politically charged music for audiences around the nation. His output included nearly three thousand songs, several novels, and other writings in the form of articles, essays, poems, and letters. In addition, Guthrie also painted, drew cartoons, and often illustrated his writings.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadafc.af001001.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:15</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.pnp/eadpnp.pp002008.2</id>
    <title>Visual materials from the Blackwell family papers</title>
    <updated>2010-11-22T18:25:30</updated>
    <summary>LOT 13267-1 is comprised of photocopies of original lantern slides illustrating events in the women's suffrage movement, ca. 1859-1928. LOT 13267-2 is comprised of portrait photographs of members of the Blackwell family, and others related to or involved in the fight for women's suffrage.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadpnp.pp002008.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:15</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.pnp/eadpnp.pp002011.2</id>
    <title>Visual Materials from the Records of the National Woman's Party</title>
    <updated>2010-11-22T18:25:29</updated>
    <summary>Includes primarily portraits of National Woman's Party (NWP) officers, suffragists, politicians and business women; NWP meetings and formal gatherings; women delegates at United Nations sessions on human and civil rights; views of the organization's headquarters at Washington, D.C.; postcards depicting women's suffrage slogans; anti-war posters from the National Council for Prevention of War, the American Friends Service Committee, and the Women's International League.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadpnp.pp002011.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:15</created>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.pnp/eadpnp.pp002009.2</id>
    <title>Visual materials from the papers of Clare Boothe Luce.</title>
    <updated>2010-11-22T18:25:29</updated>
    <summary>The collection includes photographs relating to Luce's varied careers and her personal life. Many document official activities and travels she undertook during her service as U.S. Ambassador to Italy (1953-1956); others document Luce's careers as a photojournalist, congresswoman, actress and playwright; some also show her involvement in Republican party politics. Aspects of Luce's personal life are revealed in images depicting her family; prominent friends and acquaintances; family vacations; portraits of Luce as a child and young adult. The collection also includes some portraits of Henry Luce's family; photographs of the Luce's art collection; posters advertising Luce's plays The Women, Margin for Error, and Kiss the Boys Goodbye.</summary>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://raw.github.com/edsu/lc-findingaids/master/data/eadpnp.pp002009.2.xml" type="application/ead+xml"/>
    <created xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">2010-09-27T13:58:14</created>
  </entry>
</feed>
